No.
いいえ。
donated to the Commission's made in China a
委員会の中国製製品に寄付されました。
research provided by the government city
政府市が提供する調査
and some political participants from China
中国からの政治参加者もいます
have passed this task.
このタスクをパスしました。
why not is a
なぜそうではないのか
whole woman
女性全体
moisturizer
保湿剤
effective
効果的
only
それだけ
Welcome everyone to join the feast of knowledge tonight
皆さん、今夜の知識の饗宴へのご参加を歓迎します
The topic of today's feast of knowledge is
今日の知識の饗宴のテーマは、
Holy Heaven hand dance community
ホーリーヘブンハンドダンスコミュニティ
Then let’s talk about the heat hazards and PM2.5 that are right in front of us
それでは、身近な熱害とPM2.5についてお話しましょう。
so we know that
だから私たちはそれを知っています
We live in Taipei City, New Taipei City
私たちは台北市、新北市に住んでいます。
This densely populated urban area
この人口密集市街地
For our health in this environment
この環境下で私たちの健康のために
There are many manufacturers
たくさんのメーカーがあります
Manufacturers are very dangerous
メーカーは非常に危険です
especially in this summer
特にこの夏は
hot weather
暑い天気
So what we often see
そこで、私たちがよく目にするのは、
health hazard
健康被害
are these hot temperatures
この気温は暑いですか
High temperature and so-called PM2.5
高温といわゆるPM2.5
So the Academia Sinica in this respect
したがって、この点に関して中央研究院は
There are also some basic research
基礎研究もいくつかあります
Some researchers are focusing on these
一部の研究者はこれらに焦点を当てています
Greater health
更大重健康
related topics
関連トピック
with some more basic
もう少し基本的なものを加えて
basic scientific research
基礎科学研究
hope to clarify
明確になることを願っています
There are some special situations
ここではいくつかの特殊な状況をご紹介します
also can hope to be able to say
と言えることも期待できます
tell everyone
みんなに言ってください
How do we avoid these hazards
どうすればこれらの危険を回避できるでしょうか
so today's speaker
それでは今日のスピーカー
It's researcher Long Shijun
研究者の龍詩軍です
He is our Academia Sinica
彼は私たちの中央研究院です
environmental change
環境の変化
research center
リサーチセンター
a teacher researcher
教師研究者
He is from National Taiwan University
彼は国立台湾大学の出身です
The first graduate of science from a large enterprise
大企業初の理系卒業生
sit down please give me three minutes
座って3分ほど時間をください
at Harvard University
ハーバード大学で
School of Public Health
公衆衛生学部
Got a Ph.D.
博士号を取得しました。
in a famous
有名なところで
a chair professor
一位講座教授
Under John Spankles' door
ジョン・スパンクルズのドアの下で
he has been for a long time
彼は長い間そうしている
Finally, 15 years of expertise is in the study of these thermal hazards
最後に、これらの熱的危険性の研究には 15 年間の専門知識が活かされています。
air pollution
大気汚染
These assessments of these hazards of these risks in this environment
この環境におけるこれらのリスクのこれらの危険性の評価
that uses the scientific method
それが科学的な方法です
Because some organic chemistry analysis is to be done
有機化学分析を行う必要があるため
To design the instruments for these detections
これらの検出用の機器を設計するには
especially in many specialties
特に多くの専門分野で
His expertise is mainly in the analysis of the components of organic coke
彼の専門知識は主に有機コークスの成分分析です。
Because of his achievements on such an important subject
非常に重要なテーマにおける彼の業績のおかげで
In 2004, he won the Qiusheng Award of the Taiwan Air-Coke Society
2004 年に台湾エアコーク協会の Qiusheng Award を受賞しました。
He's doing a lot of things on this side of public service at the same time
彼は公共サービスのこちら側で同時に多くのことを行っている
Participate in committees related to environmental quality or government agencies in Taipei City
台北市の環境品質に関する委員会または政府機関に参加する
so today
それで今日
he came back and told us
彼は戻ってきて私たちに言いました
probably explain
おそらく説明します
I now tell everyone
今みんなに言います
Very familiar with what is PM2.5
PM2.5とは何かについてよく知っています
contained in
に含まれた
what is basic science
基礎科学とは何ですか
Then our current
それから私たちの現在
heat hazard is what we are now
熱の危険が私たちの現状です
today
今日
at this
この時点で
July
七月
The temperature we must face
私たちが直面しなければならない温度
and the quality of our air
そして私たちの空気の質
so i thought i would
だからそうしようと思った
don't spend too much time
都不花太多的時間
us
私たち
had a great speech
素晴らしいスピーチをしました
so we ask everyone
そこで皆さんにお願いします
Welcome with loud applause
大きな拍手でお出迎え
Researcher Long Shijun
龍師俊研究員
Give us today's Sisi Banquet
今日のシシィの晩餐会を私たちにください
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you Vice President for your introduction
副社長、ご紹介ありがとうございました
Thank you all for your support on such a hot day
暑い中、応援してくださった皆様、ありがとうございました
Come to this evening
今夜来てください
this little feast of knowledge
この小さな知識の饗宴
When I was in National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学にいた頃
actually learned by
実際に学んだのは
this
これ
air mass
気団
How to transmit How to cause the diffusion of pollutants
汚染物質の伝染方法 汚染物質の拡散の原因
this aspect
この側面
but i'm in the harvard school of public health
でも私はハーバード公衆衛生大学院に通っています
What we want is actually from a human perspective
私たちが望んでいるのは、実際には人間の視点からのものです
for departure
出発に向けて
It's human-centered, let's talk about it
それは人間中心です、それについて話しましょう
What kind of environmental factors
どのような環境要因があるのか
will affect my health
私の健康に影響を与えるでしょう
OK so this neighborhood we live in
さて、私たちが住んでいるこの近所
In fact, it is the environment that most affects our quality of life.
実際、私たちの生活の質に最も影響を与えるのは環境です。
So that's what we're most concerned about
それが私たちが最も懸念していることです
The type of living in this community in Asia
アジアのこのコミュニティでの暮らし方
Not the same as Europe and the United States
ヨーロッパやアメリカと同じではない
everyone knows
みんな知ってる
because we are densely populated
私たちは人口が密集しているので
then densely populated places
それから人口密集地
Traffic is heavy again
また渋滞してるね
So our doorstep
だから私たちの玄関口
often within an hour
多くの場合1時間以内に
Thousands of vehicles will pass by
何千台もの車両が通過します
Unlike the existing residential areas in Europe and the United States
欧米の既存の住宅地とは異なります。
they may be within a day
1日以内に届くかもしれない
ten cars that will pass
10台の車が通過します
His own and his neighbor's
自分のものと隣人のもの
the exposure
露出
It's just that the exposure is completely different.
ただ露出が全然違います。
So we live in communities where there are many
ですから私たちは、たくさんの人がいるコミュニティに住んでいます。
like this close at hand
こんなに近くにあるのに
The source of traffic pollution is the catering industry that we pass through every day to and from get off work
交通公害の原因は、私たちが毎日仕事の行き帰りに通過するケータリング産業です。
Even public temples or some small factories
公立寺院や小さな工場でも
These are all sources of pollution that are in sight
これらはすべて目に見える汚染源です
When I came back to my country, I found that these Asians are very special
母国に戻ったとき、これらのアジア人はとても特別であることがわかりました。
And it is very important source of pollution to our life
そしてそれは私たちの生活にとって非常に重要な汚染源です
but few studies
でも勉強する人は少ない
so i just jumped in
だから私はただ飛び込んだ
Hope to use a scientific and systematic way
科学的かつ体系的な方法を使用したいと考えています
to study these pollution sources
これらの汚染源を研究するために
What is the incremental exposure to us?
私たちに対する暴露の増加とは何でしょうか?
What is the impact factor behind it
その背後にあるインパクトファクターは何ですか
How can we reduce its impact
どうすればその影響を軽減できるか
Protect our own health
私たち自身の健康を守る
At the same time, I myself was born with an atmosphere
同時に私自身も雰囲気を持って生まれてきました
So under climate change
したがって、気候変動の下では
everyone's getting hotter
みんな熱くなってます
So for thermal hazards I can also combine
熱の危険性のために、組み合わせることもできます
Expertise in Atmospheric Sciences and Public Health
大気科学と公衆衛生の専門知識
to discuss
話し合う
So today's talk will take these two as the topic
ということで、今日はこの二人をテーマにお話します
is how we go deep
それが私たちが深く進む方法です
How does my team go deep into the community
私のチームはどのようにしてコミュニティに深く関わっていくのでしょうか
Then study the thermal hazards in front of you and follow the 2.5
次に、目の前にある熱による危険性を調べ、2.5 の規則に従ってください。
I'll start with this
これから始めます
Start with thermal hazards
熱による危険から始める
at least
少なくとも
Well, this is, this is no longer news to everyone.
そうですね、これはもう誰にとってもニュースではありません。
That is, every year, we break records in high temperature.
つまり、毎年、高温の記録を更新しているのです。
OK, it's been three years in a row, this opinion says yes
OK、これは 3 年連続です、この意見はそうです。
hottest ever hottest ever and then set new highs three years in a row
これまでで最も暑い、これまでで最も暑い、そして 3 年連続で最高値を更新
OK so climate change becomes the norm
OK、それでは気候変動が常態化します
So we will face more and more frequent
だから私たちはますます頻繁に直面するでしょう
This heat wave continues at this high temperature
この猛暑がこの高温で続いています
Then Taiwan will be connected with the subtropical zone
そうすれば台湾は亜熱帯と繋がるだろう
Therefore, in the words of ordinary people, it is likely to think that
したがって、一般人の言葉で言えば、次のように考えられるでしょう。
I grew up in such a hot environment
こんなに暑い環境で育ったのですね
I have long adapted to the heat
私は長い間暑さに適応してきました
So it shouldn't have any effect on my health
だから健康に影響はないはず
OK, when I talked to you about heat hazards more than ten years ago
そうですね、10年以上前に私があなたと熱中症について話していたとき
The general reaction is like this, including doctors OK
医者も含めて一般的な反応はこんな感じ
let's see
どれどれ
This was ten years ago OK
これは10年前のことでした
there is sad news out
悲しいニュースが出ています
Three days of heat killed three old farmers OK
3日連続、暑さで高齢農家3人死亡 OK
After this incident, everyone realized that
この事件の後、誰もが気づいたのですが、
Taiwan may also experience heat hazards
台湾も熱害に見舞われる可能性がある
Then every year this
それから毎年これ
Such unfortunate things happen almost every summer vacation
夏休みにはこういう不幸なことが必ず起こる
Then this is this year
じゃあ今年はこれだ
ok the latest
ok 最近的
Elderly man hangs clothes for three hours and passes out due to heatstroke
高齢男性が3時間洗濯物を干し熱中症で昏倒
And he was also in the
そして彼もその中にいた
this asphalt road
このアスファルトの道路
Wounded hands twice
手を二度負傷
When I was sent to the hospital, my temperature soared above 40 degrees.
病院に運ばれたとき、私の体温は40度を超えました。
Well, such an unfortunate case
まあ、そんな残念な事件も
Fortunately, he was rescued later.
幸いなことに、彼は後に救出されました。
Then you might think that this is an isolated case
そうすると、これは特殊なケースだと思うかもしれません
Ok, what about the statistics from the Ministry of Welfare?
さて、厚生省の統計はどうですか？
In fact, it's only halfway through July
あっという間に7月も半ばですね
Nearly 300 people in Taiwan
台湾には300人近くの人がいる
All sent to the ER for heat hazard, thermal injury.
全員が熱の危険性、熱傷のためにERに送られました。
ok more than ten years ago
まあ10年以上前ですが
When we first started to study the issue of thermal hazards
私たちが最初に熱的危険性の問題を研究し始めたとき
The Ministry of Health and Welfare does not have one like this
厚生省にはこんなものはない。
Notification System of Thermal Hazards
熱的危険性の通知システム
now have
現在有了
because it is true
それは本当だから
Even the doctors in the emergency room will encounter many
救急治療室の医師でも多くの人に遭遇するでしょう。
An example of an emergency room visit due to a thermal hazard
熱害による救急外来の例
ok that's in the whole
わかりました、それは全体の中にあります
What about the World Health Organization?
世界保健機関はどうですか？
Based on our current scientific evidence
現在の科学的証拠に基づいて
to estimate future climate change scenarios
将来の気候変動シナリオを推定するため
Let me explain this A1B to you
このA1Bについて説明しましょう
In fact, it is still a medium carbon emission
実際には、依然として中程度の二酸化炭素排出量です
Even if it's not the most carbon-intensive situation
たとえそれが最も炭素集約的な状況でなくても
Even under a moderate carbon emission scenario
中程度の炭素排出シナリオの下でも
in Asia
アジアで
Regardless of whether it is a high-income country in the Asia-Pacific
アジア太平洋地域の高所得国であろうとなかろうと
or East Asia or Southeast Asia
東アジアとか東南アジアとか
Cases of additional deaths due to the impact of climate change
気候変動の影響で新たな死者が出るケースも
The number of thermal hazards is the largest
熱災害の数が最も多い
much higher than other
他よりもはるかに高い
Infectious diseases caused by climate change
気候変動による感染症
Style hot, hot, warm, thick and aggressive, etc.
ホット、ホット、ウォーム、厚くてアグレッシブなスタイルなど。
That's because the current high temperature is long
それは今の高温期が長いからです
Soar to 38, 40 in one go
一気に38、40まで上昇
It is far more than our body can bear
それは私たちの体が耐えられる量をはるかに超えています
Even these Asia-Pacific high-income countries
これらのアジア太平洋の高所得国でさえ
We say that Taiwan belongs to this
台湾はこれに属すると言う
Although we have a good infrastructure
インフラが整っているにもかかわらず、
We have good medical resources
私たちは充実した医療資源を持っています
But when the ambient temperature is so high
しかし、周囲の温度が非常に高い場合、
unless we don't go out
出かけない限り
Unless we're all locked in an air-conditioned room
私たち全員がエアコンの効いた部屋に閉じ込められていない限り
Otherwise we'd all likely be exposed to heat hazards
そうしないと、私たち全員が熱の危険にさらされる可能性があります
that would make sense
それは理にかなっています
some weaker ones
いくつかの弱いもの
Including children, the elderly, pregnant women
子ども、お年寄り、妊婦も含めて
He already had this cardiovascular disease
彼はすでにこの心臓病を患っていた
He will be exposed to heat hazards
彼は熱の危険にさらされるだろう
it may cause misfortune
それは不幸を引き起こすかもしれない
So whether this is estimated in 2030
では、これは 2030 年に推定されるかどうか
Same as the 2050 projection
2050年の予測と同じ
Thousands of people will be exposed to heat hazards
何千人もの人々が熱の危険にさらされることになる
so the countries of the world
だから世界の国々は
Therefore put this for thermal hazards
したがって、これを熱的危険に備えてください
Countermeasures
対策
is how we adjust
それが私たちが調整する方法です
OK response
OK応答
Future climate variability like this
将来の気候変動はこんな感じ
challenge to us
私たちへの挑戦
as one of their top priorities
最優先事項の 1 つとして
OK
OK
According to this methodology, Taiwan
この方法論によれば、台湾は
We also made our own estimates
独自の見積もりも作成しました
There are probably hundreds of them every year.
おそらく毎年何百件もあるでしょう。
Cases of additional deaths due to thermal hazards
熱害による追加死亡例
Most of them are also concentrated in people over the age of 65.
そのほとんどは65歳以上の人々に集中しています。
then you might think
それからあなたは思うかもしれません
is this overrated
これは過大評価ですか
People around me don't seem to have
私の周りの人はそうではないようです
How to feel the heat hazard
暑さの危険をどう感じるか
We go to work early every day at most
私たちはせいぜい毎日早く仕事に行きます
You'll be fine if you hide in an air-conditioned room
エアコンの効いた部屋に隠れていれば大丈夫
OK to share with you
シェアしてもOKです
what we do in this community
このコミュニティで私たちがやっていること
Actually go into people's homes to do measurements
実際に人の家に行って測定してみます
This is the past few years we have been in the two areas of Gaoping, Greater Taipei
これはここ数年、台北市の高平の 2 つの地域に行ってきたことです。
We recruited 62 volunteers in three communities
3 つのコミュニティで 62 人のボランティアを募集しました
Let's go to his house to measure
彼の家に測りに行きましょう
The temperature between the outdoors of his house and his indoor living room
彼の家の屋外と屋内のリビングルームの間の温度
OK, then we have the same 62 data
OK、同じ 62 個のデータがあります
We use different groupings
さまざまなグループ分けを使用します
like boys and girls
男の子と女の子のように
This age, North and South, etc.
この時代、北と南など。
Then I want to point out that it is the last item.
それから、最後の項目でございます。
He opened the window and turned on the air conditioner.
彼は窓を開けてエアコンをつけました。
Of course we all know
もちろん私たちは皆知っています
Turning on the air conditioner is of course lower than the temperature with the windows open
エアコンをつけると窓を開けたときよりも当然気温が低くなります。
But have you seen their temperature?
でも、彼らの温度を見たことがありますか？
OK, this one with the window open
OK、これは窓を開けた状態です
There are three households, and it's almost 40 degrees.
３世帯ありますが、気温は４０度近くあります。
OK this isn't our first time at home
OK、家に来るのはこれが初めてではない
40 degrees is measured inside the house
家の中で測ると40度
Actually many times
実は何度も
When I came back from the first test, I told my assistant about yours
最初のテストから戻ったとき、アシスタントにあなたのテストのことを話しました。
There's something wrong with that thermometer of yours, take it in and have it calibrated again.
あなたのその温度計には何か問題があります。それを持ってきて校正してください。
He said the calibration is fine
彼は校正は問題ないと言いました
It's not about his abandonment
それは彼の放棄ではない
That house is really 40 degrees
あの家は本当に40度です
I said why the air conditioner is not turned on at 40 degrees?
なぜ40度でもエアコンをつけないのかと言いました。
how can you bear it
どうして耐えられますか
He said that grandpa told me
おじいちゃんが私に言ったと彼は言いました
He only turns on the air conditioner when his grandson comes
彼は孫が来たときだけエアコンをオンにする
usually he is at home
普段彼は家にいます
He thinks it's amazing that I've lived like this all my life
彼は私がこれまでずっとそうやって生きてきたことをすごいと思っています。
I'm used to it
慣れてます
this is a reason
これは理由です
One reason is that the air conditioner is too costly
理由の一つはエアコンの値段が高す​​ぎること
too expensive
高すぎる
So he can't bear to leave
だから彼は離れることに耐えられない
and some housewives
そして何人かの主婦
He's actually at home because he needs to spend his own money
彼は自分のお金を使う必要があるので実際には家にいます
So they don't turn on the air conditioner
だから彼らはエアコンをつけない
Compared with our usual white-collar stage
通常のホワイトカラーステージと比較して
Blow on the air conditioner when we go to work
仕事に行くときにエアコンを吹きます
the situation is very different
状況は大きく異なります
So Taiwan does have such a situation
台湾にもそういう状況があるんだね
We are among the 62 defenders
私たちは62人のディフェンダーの一人です
There are only 13 people who turn on the air conditioner
エアコンをつけるのは13人だけ
And he is actually in the middle of the air-conditioning
そして彼は実際にエアコンの真っ只中にいます
Because we measured and found
測って見つけたから
His indoor and outdoor temperature
彼の屋内と屋外の温度
In fact, the correlation is as high as 0.9
実際、相関関係は 0.9 にもなります。
We just wondered how is it possible?
なぜそんなことが可能なのか？
If you turn on the air conditioner for a long time
エアコンを長時間つけていると
Shouldn't the temperature be this low?
こんなに気温低くなくてもいいのでは？
First, they didn't turn on the air conditioner very low.
まず、エアコンの温度をあまり下げませんでした。
This is the first point because it saves power
節電のための第一のポイントです
The second one is very honest if there are several
2 つ目は、複数ある場合は非常に正直です
talk to my assistant
私のアシスタントと話してください
that's because you're coming
それはあなたが来るからです
So we were the first ten minutes
だから私たちは最初の10分間だった
just turn on the air conditioner
ただエアコンをつけてください
for going to meet him
彼に会いに行くために
just feel sorry
ただ残念に思う
Someone has guests and the house is very hot
誰かが来客していて、家はとても暑いです
OK so in this case
OK、この場合は
So their correlation calculation is quite high
したがって、相関計算は非常に高いです
So this means that
つまり、これは次のことを意味します
We are actually in this ordinary household
私たちは実はこの普通の家庭にいます
There are many situations that do exist
実際に存在する状況はたくさんあります
is that they may all be potential
それらはすべて潜在的な可能性があるということです
Possible Groups of Thermal Hazards
考えられる熱害のグループ
Because they generally don't turn on the air conditioner at home
普段家ではエアコンをつけないので
ok so this is the show saying
OK、これは番組が言っていることです
our taiwan words
私たちの台湾の言葉
In fact, we have to formulate this dark countermeasure
実はこの闇の対策を練る必要がある
is to adjust
調整することです
The government needs to adjust the strategy
政府は戦略を調整する必要がある
is very very important
とてもとても重要です
then our scientific community
それから私たちの科学コミュニティ
How can we help the government to
政府ができることをどのように支援できるか
What about the adjustment strategy for this thermal hazard?
この熱的危険に対する厳密な調整戦略はありますか?
The first thing we can do is
まず私たちにできることは、
we can do this
できるよ
In this rigorous climate change adaptation strategy
この厳格な気候変動適応戦略において
Advance Scientific Assessment Process
高度な科学的評価プロセス
Vulnerability Assessment
脆弱性評価
it's easy to say
言うのは簡単です
But it's also very complicated and difficult to do
しかし、それは非常に複雑で難しいことでもあります
The first is to figure out what are the highly vulnerable communities
1 つ目は、非常に脆弱なコミュニティが何かを把握することです
Vulnerability by definition
定義上の脆弱性
Briefly introduce to you
簡単にご紹介します
It actually has three aspects
実はこれには3つの側面がある
This is also very intuitive
これも非常に直感的です
The first is how much heat hazard I'm exposed to
1つ目は、どのくらいの熱の危険にさらされているかです
This is exposure
これが露出です
but the same exposure
でも同じ露出
some people can stand it some people can't
耐えられる人もいるし、耐えられない人もいる
For example, if I have a heart vessel
たとえば、私に心臓の血管があるとします。
I'm weak if I have a disease
病気になると体が弱くなる
So the same heat is for me
だから同じ熱が私にもある
may not be able to bear
耐えられないかもしれない
OK
OK
So this sensitive word
だからこのセンシティブな言葉は
It's a person's physique
それは人の体格です
personal physical characteristics
個人の身体的特徴
including the older
年上の人も含めて
pregnant women
妊娠中の女性
fetus
胎児
very young child
とても幼い子供
this is sensitivity
これが感性です
Or the underprivileged who are involved in sperm, etc.
あるいは精子に関わる恵まれない人たちなど。
if you come again
また来たら
Responsiveness should also be considered
対応力も考慮する必要がある
words of resilience
立ち直る言葉
means
意味
Is there any way for me to deal with the heat hazard from the outside world?
外界からの熱の危険に対処する方法はありますか?
I hid in the air-conditioned room
エアコンの効いた部屋に隠れた
This is the best countermeasure
これが一番の対策です
OK so I can do it in my profession
わかった、本職でやってもいいよ
But many people's occupations cannot do this.
しかし、多くの人の職業ではこれができません。
So it may not be able to cope well
なのでうまく対応できないかも知れません
So which are
それでどれが
That's because the sensitivity is mostly a matter of personal constitution
なぜなら、敏感さはほとんどが個人の体質の問題だからです。
So the main thing we want to discuss here is
ここで私たちが議論したい主なことは、
Who are the high-risk groups
高リスクグループとは誰ですか
Who are the low ability groups
能力の低いグループは誰ですか
Can we find out the features
特徴がわかるでしょうか
Therefore, social welfare units can target these
したがって、社会福祉部門はこれらをターゲットにすることができます
The words of this highly sensitive and vulnerable community
非常に敏感で脆弱なコミュニティの言葉
Then come here and do something better
それならここに来てもっと良いことをしてください
This measure of prevention, sanitation, etc.
予防や衛生などのこの措置。
The questions we have to answer then include
私たちが答えなければならない質問には以下が含まれます：
Are the people actually
本当にその人たちはいるのか
He actually suffers from heat hazard levels
彼は実際に熱中症の危険レベルに苦しんでいます
is it really serious
それは本当に深刻ですか
Are there any high-risk communities?
高リスクのコミュニティはありますか?
what is his actual risk
彼の実際のリスクは何ですか
that for
それのための
If we're going to talk about thermal hazards
熱による危険性について話すなら
but more important
しかし、もっと重要なこと
how to deal with it
それにどう対処するか
OK
OK
Coping
対処
In terms of countries around the world
世界各国で言えば
Most Important Coping Strategies
最も重要な対処戦略
All thermal hazard warnings
すべての熱的危険性の警告
OK
OK
just to tell you in advance
事前にお伝えしておきます
heat is coming
熱が来ています
We have heat for days
何日も暑いです
So everyone spend less time outside
そのため、誰もが外で過ごす時間を減らします
or drink more water
または水をもっと飲む
then wipe your face more
それからもっと顔を拭いてください
sweating etc.
発汗など
is to use this prior prevention
この事前予防策を使用することです
So if we want to have this
それで、これを手に入れたい場合は、
word on heat warning system
暑さ警報システムに関するお知らせ
Which one is the appropriate heat hazard index for Taiwan?
台湾にとって適切な暑さ危険指数はどれですか?
So if we're going to issue a heat warning like this
では、このように暑さ警報を発令するとしたら、
We need to find the appropriate pre-limit value
適切な事前制限値を見つける必要があります
So this is all science
つまり、これはすべて科学なのです
can help to answer this question
この質問に答えるのに役立ちます
this is our team
これが私たちのチームです
this direction of this effort
この取り組みのこの方向性
so let me introduce
それで紹介しましょう
is how we go
それが私たちのやり方です
Find out which are the most vulnerable communities
最も脆弱なコミュニティを特定する
OK
OK
In fact, in the past few years, if we
実際、ここ数年で、
very hard
とても厳しい
we follow this survey
私たちはこの調査に従っています
Cooperation with the Research Center of the Academy of Industry
産業アカデミー研究センターとの協力
Telephone interview conducted by OK Face-to-face interview
電話面接OK 対面面接
then we also
それなら私たちも
Trying to take advantage of this relatively advanced network
この比較的先進的なネットワークを活用しようとしています
The Crowdsourcing Approach The Information Science Approach
クラウドソーシングのアプローチ 情報科学のアプローチ
Cooperate with the teachers of the information center
情報センターの先生方と協力してください
Ways to do research with mobile phones Online research
携帯電話でリサーチする方法 オンラインリサーチ
In fact, if it is a telephone interview or a face-to-face interview
実際、電話面接や対面面接であれば、
Of course the cost is high
もちろんコストは高いですが
OK, online surveys are cheaper than mobile surveys
OK、オンライン アンケートはモバイル アンケートよりも安価です
And it can have 4,000 or 8,000 copies in two weeks
2 週間で 4,000 部または 8,000 部になる可能性があります
wow so fast so great
うわー、とても速い、とても素晴らしい
So I can after the heat hazard comes
暑さの危険が来ても大丈夫です
go to this survey
このアンケートに行く
this is very good
これはすごくいい
what a pity
お気の毒に
everyone will know
誰もが知っているでしょう
Who will actually fill in these questionnaires on the Internet and on the mobile phone?
インターネットや携帯電話でこれらのアンケートに実際に記入するのは誰ですか?
just young people
ただの若者たち
Young people are not a highly vulnerable group of heat hazards at all.
若者は熱中症に対して非常に脆弱なグループではありません。
so it becomes
そうなります
This method is scientifically feasible
この方法は科学的に実現可能です
We also built something like this
こんなものも作りました
Crowdsource this survey method
この調査方法をクラウドソーシングする
Unfortunately not so suitable for use in this heat hazard
残念ながら、この熱の危険での使用にはあまり適していません
So we later or later
それで私たちは後になっても後になっても
The information for this interview was done at a lot of cost.
このインタビューの情報提供には多額の費用がかかりました。
In terms of noodle shops
蕎麦屋と言えば
eighty percent
80パーセント
we smoked this
私たちはこれを吸った
Respondent's words
回答者の言葉
would reject us
私たちを拒否するだろう
So we're going to draw 10,000
じゃあ10,000人引くよ
The middle two thousand finally succeeded
真ん中の2000がついに成功しました
Telephone visits have a higher rate of giant visits
電話による訪問の方が巨人訪問率が高い
90%
90%
But these actual visits
しかし、これらの実際の訪問は、
is able to give us
私たちに与えることができます
very in-depth information
非常に詳しい情報
Let's go into more detail
さらに詳しく見てみましょう
scientific discussion
科学的な議論
The words here are also sincere, please everyone
ここの言葉も誠実ですので皆さんよろしくお願いします
If you get a call some day
いつか電話がかかってきたら
investigate or
調べるか、
remember to the end
最後まで覚えておいてください
Plus say you want to interview
さらに、面接したいと伝えてください
please say yes
良いと言って
science that can help us
私たちを助けることができる科学
Research
研究
So we base this
したがって、これをベースにします
The interview information
インタビュー情報
explore
探検
High-risk groups and low-hard ability groups
高リスクグループと低能力グループ
feature
特徴
When these features are many
これらの機能が多い場合
Sincerely
心から
Our first focus is
私たちの最初の焦点は、
He was forced to spend a lot of time outside
彼は多くの時間を外で過ごさざるを得なくなった
What are the characteristics of which communities?
どのコミュニティにはどのような特徴があるのでしょうか?
OK, the male is less educated
そうですね、男性は教育を受けていません
Part-time jobs for remote witnesses
遠隔証人のためのアルバイト
Also engaged in these industries
こんな業界にも携わってます
Agriculture, forestry, cloud, wood, mining, manufacturing and construction
農業、林業、クラウド、木材、鉱業、製造業、建設業
or wholesale shipping
または卸売配送
Some of them are known from the literature
それらのいくつかは文献で知られています
but some are not
しかしそうでない人もいます
Include wholesale shipping like this
このように卸売配送を含めます
We thought he drove a big truck
私たちは彼が大型トラックを運転しているのだと思った
He actually has air conditioning in the car
実は車内にエアコンが付いているんです
We actually asked a few drivers
実際に何人かのドライバーに聞いてみた
He said some cars were simply too old
彼は、いくつかの車は単に古すぎると言いました
I can't turn on the air conditioner at all
エアコンが全くつけられない
I turn on the air conditioner and the engine gets wet
エアコンをつけるとエンジンが濡れてしまう
this is a little
これはちょっと
The second point he said
彼が言った2番目のポイントは
In fact, many of us smoke
実際、私たちの多くは喫煙します
so if we smoke
それで私たちがタバコを吸ったら
The windows won't close at all
窓が全然閉まらない
So they won't turn on the air conditioner
だから彼らはエアコンをつけない
Because you didn't turn on the air conditioner
エアコンをつけなかったから
OK so they become
OK、こうなります
longer time outdoors
屋外で長時間過ごす
They spend more time in the sun
彼らは太陽の下でより多くの時間を過ごします
It's like this, this has such characteristics
こんな感じです、これはこんな特徴があります
Then everyone because of the cold
それでは皆様、寒いので
In this regard, I just mentioned
この点に関しては、先ほども述べたように、
In fact, some households do not have air-conditioning or use less air-conditioning
実際、エアコンがない、またはエアコンの使用量が少ない家庭もあります。
Like the family elders who don't have a high description in this family, etc.
この家族の中でそれほど地位の高い人物ではない家族の長老たちなど。
As for these materials, we will also provide them to the Ministry of Health and Welfare’s Social Housing and Family Affairs Bureau.
これらの資料につきましては、厚生省の社会住宅家庭局にも提供させていただきます。
their social workers said
彼らのソーシャルワーカーは言いました
Their social workers have already made calls in hot weather.
実際、彼らのソーシャルワーカーはすでに暑い天候の中で電話をかけています。
To care for these elders in the ethnic group to remind them that
これらの老人たちを世話し、彼らに次のことを思い出させること
Drink plenty of water, rest more, don't go out in hot weather, etc.
水をたくさん飲む、もっと休む、暑い季節には外出しないなど。
OK, everyone can do this
OK、これは誰でもできます
Okay, let's take a look at our province's actual
さて、私たちの州の実際の状況を見てみましょう
More than 2000 respondents
2000人以上の回答者
To find these more than 2,000 respondents, we must not be alone.
これら 2,000 人を超える回答者を見つけるには、私たちだけではいけません。
So we are also with this research center
私たちもこの研究センターにいます
Together, 25 interviewers were trained and then
25 人の面接官が一緒にトレーニングを受け、
Visit these 50 villages across the province
州内の 50 の村を訪ねてみましょう
Then our execution period is from the genus to the autumnal equinox
それでは実行期間は本年から秋分までとなります。
In fact, there may be autumn tigers in the middle
実は真ん中に秋の虎がいるかも知れません
Then this visit
それから今回の訪問は
It's actually very special
実はとても特別なのです
This is the first time environmental science and social scientists have collaborated
環境科学と社会科学者が協力するのはこれが初めてです
So these interviewers' questionnaires were
したがって、これらのインタビュアーのアンケートは次のとおりでした。
Not just to ask social questions
社会的な質問をするだけではなく
Also ask environmental science questions
環境科学に関する質問もする
Even more powerful
さらに強力に
they actually
彼らは実際に
we also train them
私たちも彼らを訓練します
Help us carry the temperature and humidity in quarantine
検疫中の温度と湿度の管理にご協力ください
and photodetector
と光検出器
to monitor the environmental conditions inside and outside their homes
家の内外の環境状態を監視する
OK
OK
So you see these little boxes in front of you
目の前にこれらの小さな箱が見えます
It's all these quarantine-style environments.
これらすべてが隔離スタイルの環境です。
Talk about quarantine
隔離について話す
But it is the precision that must be able to conform to scientific data
ただし、科学的データに準拠できなければならないのは精度です。
OK
OK
The data can also be transmitted
データ送信も可能
good
良い
That's how it works
それが仕組みです
We also provide
また、
The person from the family of the Ministry of Health and Welfare
厚生省のご家族の方
we just say
言ってみよう
your social worker
あなたのソーシャルワーカー
during home visits
家庭訪問中に
Maybe take a quarantine test with you.
検疫テストも一緒に受けたほうがいいかもしれません。
The indoor and outdoor temperature of his old man's house
老人の家の屋内と屋外の温度
This will help them clarify
これは彼らが明確にするのに役立ちます
What kind of old people
一体どんな老人たちなのか
In fact, I usually don't turn on the air conditioner at home.
実は、私は普段家ではエアコンをつけません。
OK
OK
So you can find this advanced
この高度な機能を見つけることができます
vulnerable communities
脆弱なコミュニティ
What we are talking about today is testing
今日私たちが話しているのはテストについてです
Detect environmental conditions inside and outside the home
家の内外の環境状態を検出
means we are testing
私たちがテストしていることを意味します
the extent of its thermal hazard
熱的危険性の程度
We want him to understand the extent of its heat hazard
私たちは彼にその熱の危険性の程度を理解してもらいたい
So we're going to the next question
それでは次の質問に行きます
What is the appropriate indicator of thermal hazards in Taiwan
台湾における熱災害の適切な指標は何ですか
This is a few years ago in New York
これは数年前のニューヨークでの話です
Rarely does the mass media address this
マスコミがこの件を取り上げることはほとんどない
Proposed that heat is not just high temperature
熱は単なる高温ではないことを提唱
The terrifying combination of temperature and humidity is even more terrifying
恐ろしい温度と湿度の組み合わせはさらに恐ろしい
So we all know in Taiwan
だから台湾ではみんな知ってるよ
If also under the condition of high temperature
高温条件下でも
if the humidity is high
湿度が高い場合
We can't sweat out
汗をかくことができない
So we will feel more heat and pressure
だから私たちはより多くの熱と圧力を感じるでしょう
OK more sad
OK、もっと悲しい
So humidity is a very important factor to consider
したがって、湿度は考慮すべき非常に重要な要素です
in meteorology
気象学で
We learned it when we were sophomores
私たちは二年生のときに習いました
There is a comprehensive index of temperature and humidity called damp heat index
湿度指数という温度と湿度を総合した指標があります。
OK
OK
But what about the humidity index?
しかし、湿度指数はどうでしょうか？
In fact, it's just looking at everyone's thermal comfort.
実際、それは全員の温熱快適性を調べているだけです。
It's called Somal Comfort
それはソマルコンフォートと呼ばれています
It's whether you are comfortable or not
それはあなたが快適かどうかです
It is based on a questionnaire
アンケートをもとに作成しています
so just ask you
それで聞いてください
you are in this environment
あなたはこの環境にいます
Is your work efficiency good?
仕事の効率は良いですか？
Are you in a good mood? Wait a minute
機嫌はいいですか? ちょっと待ってください
It doesn't really ask us now
今は特に問いません
most concerned about climate change
気候変動を最も懸念している
Somal Stress is heat pressure
ソーマルストレスは熱圧力です
heat hazard
熱の危険性
It's just my body index is fast
ただ私のボディインデックスが速いだけです
It's just the heart beating
ただ心臓が動いているだけです
I'm dying
私は死ぬ
I'm about to pour that before
その前にそれを注ぐつもりです
do i want to prevent this
これを防ぎたいですか？
not if i'm in a good mood
機嫌が良ければそうではない
or something uncomfortable
または何か不快なこと
So Somal is
それでソマルは
For comfort and heat stress
快適さと熱ストレスのために
Thermal hazards are a different concept
熱的危険性は別の概念です
So what about public health?
では、公衆衛生についてはどうなのでしょうか？
In fact, there are more suitable
実際には、もっと適切なものがあります
of public health
公衆衛生の
The heat hazard index
熱中症指数
OK then we all know
OK、それならみんな知ってるよ
if in
もし入っているなら
If it is windy this summer
今年の夏、風が強かったら
wow so comfortable
うわーとても快適
so there is a lot of wind
だから風が多いです
So wind speed is another factor to consider
したがって、風速も考慮すべきもう一つの要素です
Therefore, in addition to temperature and humidity, wind speed is very important
したがって、温度と湿度に加えて、風速も非常に重要です
one more
もう一つ
You see that girl breaks up in summer
ほら、あの子は夏に別れるのよ
On the one hand, I am afraid of getting sunburned.
一方で日焼けは怖いです。
On the other hand, each umbrella has a shadow
一方で傘にはそれぞれ影がある
not exposed to direct sunlight
直射日光にさらされないこと
we are much more comfortable
私たちはずっと快適です
So in fact by the sun
それで実際には太陽のそばで
Is it solar radiation from direct sunlight
直射日光からの日射ですか
It actually affects our own heat
実際に私たち自身の熱に影響を与えます
this symptom of this body
この体のこの症状
It is clear
明らかです
So temperature and humidity
ということで、気温と湿度
wind speed and solar radiation
風速と日射量
All four factors are important
4つの要素はすべて重要です
That
それか
There is actually such an index in public health
公衆衛生学には実際にそのような指標があります
It's called the neutralization temperature heat index
それは中和温度熱指数と呼ばれます
The solution is called WBGT
この解決策は WBGT と呼ばれます
It is to consider these four
この４つを考えることです
this indicator
このインジケーター
Then this WBGT is actually in public health
それでは、この WBGT は実際に公衆衛生上に存在します。
In the case of labor
労働の場合
Labor safety and health has already been used
労働安全衛生はすでに使用されています
seventy years
70年
His early years were developed by the United States Marine Corps
彼の初期の頃はアメリカ海兵隊によって開発されました
He noticed that when the soldiers were practicing
彼は兵士たちが訓練しているときに気づいた
or in a submarine
あるいは潜水艦の中
In the case of high temperature and sweltering heat close to the boiler
ボイラー付近の高温・灼熱の場合
They use the physiological response of soldiers
彼らは兵士の生理学的反応を利用しています
Classify it like this
このように分類すると
The most serious is WBGT above 32.2
最も深刻なのはWBGTが32.2を超える場合です
is black flag
黒旗です
The black flag indicates that the company's soldiers are physically strong
黒い旗は中隊の兵士が肉体的に強いことを示しています
No able-bodied soldier should be in that situation
健常者の兵士はそのような状況に陥るべきではない
prolonged exposure to the sun
太陽に長時間さらされる
or prolonged exercise
または長時間の運動
So this is the black flag
つまりこれは黒旗だ
After these five categories are also used in
これらの 5 つのカテゴリは以下でも使用されます。
On the Classification of Occupational Safety and Health in the World
世界における労働安全衛生の分類について
someone mentioned
誰かが言及した
Both soldiers and labor friends are in good shape
兵士も労働者の友人も健康状態が良い
Are their indicators suitable for ordinary people?
彼らの指標は一般の人に適していますか？
Therefore, some domestic scholars have also studied
そのため、国内の学者も研究を行っています。
Indeed, from the health insurance database
確かに、健康保険データベースより
Mortality rate of all causes of death in Taiwan
台湾のすべての死因による死亡率
Significant increase above WBGT35°
WBGT35°を超えると大幅に増加
In terms of the total rescue rate
合計救出率で見ると
Significant increase above WBGT33 degrees
WBGT33度を超えると大幅に増加
WBGT actually uses cost as its standard
WBGT は実際にはコストを基準として使用します
Because it is actually three
本当は3つなので
It is the wet bulb temperature, the black bulb temperature and the air temperature are the sum of degrees
湿球温度は黒球温度と気温の合計です。
it has a weight added to each other
お互いに重みが加わります
We also talked with Mr. Tang Jingsheng from the Department of Public Health of Fuzhou University
福州大学公衆衛生学部のTang Jingsheng氏とも話をしました。
I also read that it is suitable for the general public
一般向けにも適しているとも読みました
Is that suitable for the elderly?
それは高齢者にも適していますか？
So Mr. Tang here
それで、タンさん、ここにいます
healthy elderly
健康な高齢者
Then let's compare WBGT with other evil indexes that we are familiar with
次に、WBGT を私たちがよく知っている他の邪悪な指標と比較してみましょう
Let's talk about these for the elderly
高齢者向けにこれについて話しましょう
Which is the most appropriate indicator of harm
害を示す最も適切な指標はどれですか
After comparison, it is still WBGT
比較してもWBGTのままです
So to show this WBGT it can actually be shown to the general public
この WBGT を実際に一般の人々に見せることができるのです。
What's more, it is suitable for the sensitive group that is the most important to this heat hazard
さらに、この熱害に対して最も重要な敏感層にも適しています。
is the old man
老人です
So we know that with WBGT
WBGT でそれがわかります
So if we are indoors
だから私たちが屋内にいるなら
We use WBGT to measure
WBGTを使用して測定します
The luminosity we measured, etc.
測定した明るさなど
In the end, it is converted into the index of WBGT
最終的にはWBGTのインデックスに変換されます
Then our total
それから私たちの合計
Its practical questionnaire has interviewed more than 2,000 households
実践的なアンケートは 2,000 世帯以上にインタビューしました
But we have limited equipment
しかし、私たちの設備には限りがあります
So only more than 500 households accept our indoor testing
そのため、屋内でのテストを受け入れているのは 500 世帯以上です
Then the last data is exactly 500
最後のデータはちょうど 500 です
What about the middle 500?
500の真ん中あたりはどうでしょうか？
There is this 20% and the other 36%
この 20% と残りの 36% があります
5% of the total are red flags and black flags
全体の 5% は赤旗と黒旗です
OK
OK
The words of the red flag mean that the community with a sense of co-branding is likely to pay attention
赤旗の文言は、共同ブランド意識を持つコミュニティが注目する可能性が高いことを意味します
it shouldn't stay in that environment for too long
その環境に長時間留まるべきではありません
So in total there are 26 households
合計26世帯になります
What about the 26 households?
26世帯はどうなるのでしょうか？
it this game is black flag family
このゲームはブラックフラッグファミリーです
it is
それはです
The temperature in the room, if they have a thermometer in the house
家に温度計がある場合、部屋の温度
The indoor temperature has actually reached more than 4 billion
室内温度は実に40億度以上に達している
So they actually know just by looking at the thermometer
つまり、彼らは温度計を見るだけで実際に知っているのです
They should do some adjustments
彼らはいくつかの調整をすべきだ
whether it's going out for a walk
散歩に出かけるかどうか
We actually had
私たちは実際に持っていました
One of the grandmothers, their house is really often more than 40 degrees
おばあちゃんの一人、彼らの家は本当に頻繁に40度を超えます
His home is Xishai, ok
彼の家は西沙です、わかりました
then we say
それから私たちは言います
Let's just say that the temperature in your era is too high
ただ言っておきますが、あなたの時代は気温が高すぎます
So if you usually say, is it when you are drying in the stream
で、普段言うと小川で干している時でしょうか？
What do you do, do you often drink water?
あなたは何をしますか、水をよく飲みますか
how about washing your face
顔を洗ったらどうですか
He still laughs at us, ok
彼はまだ私たちを笑っています、わかりました
He laughed and said, I'm not that stupid
彼は笑って言った、「私はそんなに愚かではない」
He said that when the temperature reaches 40 degrees, I will
気温が40度になったら、と彼は言いました。
Hiding out, I hid in a nearby hypermarket
隠れて近くのスーパーマーケットに隠れた
Blow off the air conditioner
エアコンを吹き飛ばす
ok, but luckily the old grandma is nearby
わかった、でも幸運なことに、年老いたおばあちゃんが近くにいる
There is a hypermarket within 15 minutes of this walk
徒歩15分以内にスーパーマーケットがあります
So if people in remote areas probably don't have
したがって、遠隔地の人々がおそらく持っていないとしても、
Then he has nowhere to hide
そうなると彼には隠れる場所がない
ok so there are a lot of these
わかりました、たくさんあります
Well, if two of them don't have air-conditioning at all
そうですね、2人にエアコンがなかったら
this device
この装置
Other words are reluctant or do not need to open
他の単語は気が進まない、または開く必要がない
Nine people thought that the temperature at that time was not bad, just right
その時の気温は大丈夫、ちょうどいいと思った人が9人
if he really has hot room sex
もし彼が本当にホットルームセックスをしているなら
it's okay
それは大丈夫
But what we're afraid of is that he doesn't feel it himself.
しかし、私たちが恐れているのは、彼自身がそれを感じていないということです。
Because like some old people, he is old after all
一部の老人と同じように、彼も結局は老人だから
He feels a little slower
彼は少し遅く感じます
what is afraid is what is said
怖いのは言われることだ
It's too late when they feel this discomfort
この不快感を感じた時には手遅れです
OK
OK
So for these households
ですから、こういった家庭にとっては、
In fact, all the more than 500 households
実際、500世帯以上のすべての世帯が、
We'll all be based on the condition of his room
私たちは皆、彼の部屋の状況に基づいて判断します
Will give a feedback at the end
最後にフィードバックします
Just suggest that they can be in the summer
夏になる可能性があることを示唆してください
what to do when it's hot
暑いときはどうするか
accommodating behavior
順応的な行動
including air conditioning
エアコンを含む
then drink more water
それからもっと水を飲みます
And actually there is a meaning to tell us
そして実は私たちに伝える意味があるのです
not just drink more water
ただ水をもっと飲むだけではなく
It is better to drink more jelly or jade
ゼリーや翡翠をもっと飲んだほうがいいです
He said it's because it's a jelly-like jelly
ゼリー状だからだそうです。
So drink the water in the stomach sometimes
だから時々お腹の中の水を飲みましょう
If you just rush out, it will make you electrolytically swell
急いで出すと電解で腫れてしまいます
unbalanced
アンバランスな
What if it's Aiyu or this fairy grass?
アイユやこの妖精草だったらどうする？
He was frozen in the frontier
彼は辺境で凍りついていた
After the festival, he will discharge it slowly
祭りが終わったらゆっくりと排出していきます
So it's better for our body
だから私たちの体にとっても良いのです
OK
OK
So we all gave him these opinions
そこで私たちは皆、彼にこれらの意見を出しました
hope is good for them
希望は彼らにとって良いことだ
Then we also put these relevant information
次に、これらの関連情報も掲載します
also gave this
これもあげました
The Social Welfare Department of the Ministry of Health and Welfare is a reference
厚生省社会福祉部が参考になります
ok so we're indoors
はい、屋内です
There are tests like this
このようなテストもあります
Then we are also in the community
それなら私たちもコミュニティにいます
OK
OK
We put this quarantine room
私たちはこの隔離室を設置しました
This meteorological observation instrument with solar cold plate
太陽冷却板を搭載した気象観測装置
Measure the temperature of these greenhouses
これらの温室の温度を測定してください
Wind speed, solar radiation, etc.
風速、日射量など
Then these words are spread infinitely
そしてこの言葉は無限に広がっていく
Integrate with our partners
パートナーとの統合
Go to this network platform of Mr. Chen Fangzhang of this information center
このインフォメーションセンターの陳芳章氏のネットワークプラットフォームにアクセスしてください
that these this
これらはこれ
Actual measurements in the community
コミュニティでの実測値
we are actually
私たちは実際に
specially placed
特別に置かれた
Everyone will walk and pass
誰もが歩いて通り過ぎます
Like asphalt road, red brick road
アスファルトの道、赤レンガの道のように
or on the cobblestone road
あるいは石畳の道で
Because that's what everyone actually does every day
それは実際に誰もが毎日やっていることだから
This situation of thermal hazards actually received
実際に受けた熱害の様子
Then everyone knows how the Meteorological Bureau measures since they were young, right?
そうすると、気象庁がどのように測っているかはみんな小さい頃から知っていますよね？
The standard test is a white house in the middle of the grass
標準テストは草の真ん中にある白い家です
Baiye Township. The inside of Baiye Township should not be exposed to direct sunlight.
白業郷: 白業郷内は直射日光にさらさないでください。
But when we are outside, we are directly exposed to the sun.
しかし、外に出ると、私たちは太陽の光に直接さらされます。
Below us is the asphalt road.
眼下にはアスファルトの道路が続いています。
So what is the purpose of the weather bureau testing him?
それでは、気象庁が彼を検査する目的は何でしょうか？
not for going
行くためではない
uh measure our heat hazard
ああ、私たちの熱の危険性を測定してください
He is here to say
彼は言うためにここにいます
Meteorological data should be able to be used as a reference with other countries
気象データは他国との参考として利用できるべきである
So they must have a standard measurement method
したがって、標準的な測定方法が必要です
But this standard measurement method is not suitable for us to measure this thermal hazard
しかし、この標準的な測定方法は、この熱的危険性を測定するのには適していません。
So we are in each
だから私たちはそれぞれの中にいます
The words of the community are actually measuring their actual thermal hazard
コミュニティの言葉は、実際の熱害を実際に測定しています。
that traditionally
それは伝統的に
uh industry
呃工業
It should be said that public health
公衆衛生と言うべきだろう
We measure thermal hazard
熱的危険性を測定します
this
これ
The instrument used is actually this one
実際に使用した楽器はこれです
Well we're going to call him a gauge for WBGT
さて、私たちは彼をWBGTゲージと呼ぶことにします
If this station
この駅なら
he has a black ball temperature
彼は黒い球の温度を持っています
This is very important and related to radiation measurement.
これは非常に重要であり、放射線測定に関連します。
Now some meteorological units in various countries in the world already know the parameter of WBGT
現在、世界のさまざまな国のいくつかの気象機関はすでに WBGT のパラメータを知っています。
But they haven't been able to put WBGT into the program, which they think is harmful to the index.
しかし、彼らはインデックスに有害であると考えているWBGTをプログラムに組み込むことができていない。
Within this early warning system
この早期警戒システム内で
The main reason is that these standard meteorological conditions around the world
主な理由は、これらの標準的な気象条件が世界中で発生しているためです。
Meteorological parameters measured Meteorological parameters
測定された気象パラメータ 気象パラメータ
There is no way to convert it into this black ball temperature
この黒い球の温度に換算する方法はありません
There is no way to convert it into black ball temperature
黒球温度に換算する方法はありません
So you can't use the WBGT classification we just talked about
したがって、先ほど説明した WBGT 分類は使用できません。
There is a final reasoning in the middle
途中に最終的な推理がある
Our team tried to find a way to connect the last line of reasoning
私たちのチームは推論の最後の行を結び付ける方法を見つけようとしました
We also checked the literature
文献も調べてみました
In fact, there are already many
実はすでにたくさんあるのですが、
It should be said that there are several articles
いくつかの記事があると言うべきです
Use meteorological instruments and WBGT to do this comparison in a certain place
気象観測機器と WBGT を使用して、特定の場所でこの比較を行います
Then do this experience room
じゃあこの体験室をやってみよう
But this experience room can often be used in Japan, but it cannot
ただし、この体験室は日本ではよく利用できるのですが、
not available in Taiwan
台湾では利用できません
Why is Japanese?
なぜ日本語なのでしょうか？
It is very different in this environment
この環境では大きく異なります
OK
OK
So it is subject to local restrictions
したがって、地域の制限を受けることになります
Fortunately, we found one
幸いなことに、私たちは 1 つを見つけました
is in the literature is a national laboratory of the United States
文献にあるのは米国の国立研究所です
it made
それが作られました
It is a way of theoretically deriving heat transfer
熱伝達を理論的に導き出す方法です
Deduced
推定
In the end our meteorological parameters
結局のところ、私たちの気象パラメータは
How to convert to WBGT
WBGTへの変換方法
But what about the transformation of this?
しかし、この変化はどうでしょうか？
It has only been tested at five locations in the US
米国内の 5 か所でのみテストされています
Not tested anywhere else
他ではテストされていません
It's like Taiwan's high temperature and high humidity
台湾の高温多湿みたいな感じですね
So we also have to come to Taiwan to test
だから私たちもテストのために台湾に来なければなりません
so we are in taiwan
それで私たちは台湾にいます
in this North Central South
この北中南部で
At least ten communities were tested before and after
前後で少なくとも 10 のコミュニティがテストされました
different types of communities
さまざまなタイプのコミュニティ
ok then we are
わかりました、それでは私たちです
In this use the meteorological parameters just now
ここでは、先ほどの気象パラメータを使用します
After measuring the meteorological parameters, it is transformed into this theoretical room
気象パラメータを測定した後、この理論的な部屋に変換されます。
we get a
を取得します
The estimated value of this routine observation
今回の定期観測の推定値
OK
OK
Then compare it to WBGT
次にWBGTと比較します。
This instrument traditionally
この楽器は伝統的に
Compare with the instrument actually used in public health
実際に公衆衛生で使用されている機器と比較してください
Everyone can take a look
誰でも見ることができます
In fact, the correlation is very good
実際、相関関係は非常に良好です
0.99 then its synergy is 1
0.99 の場合、シナジーは 1
We have accumulated more than 3000 records
3000件以上の実績が蓄積されています
ok
Ok
After getting this information
この情報を入手してから
of course we are happy
もちろん私たちは幸せです
Then I went to my senior from the Meteorological Bureau and said
そこで私は気象庁の先輩にこう言いました。
Hey senior, it can be used now, right?
先輩、もう使えるんですよね？
You see we continue to do so well in Taiwan
私たちは台湾で引き続き好調を維持しています
So you can use this WBGT as the indicator of the stomach damage index, right?
このWBGTを胃のダメージ指数の指標として使えるということですね。
He said hey girl
彼は「やあ、お嬢さん」と言いました
You have studied meteorology for so long
あなたは気象学を長い間研究してきました
do not you know
知りませんか
The weather bureau's most important thing is the forecast
気象庁にとって最も重要なのは天気予報です
what you can't predict
予測できないこと
so I'm useless
だから私は駄目なんだ
You told me that your measured values ​​are very close
測定値が非常に近いと言われました
It's useless
無駄だ
To be accurate
正確に言うと
good
良い
So we spent a lot of effort
それで私たちは多大な努力を費やしました
I will find teacher Lin Chuanyao from our center
私たちのセンターからリン・チュアンヤオ先生を探します
He also has a forecast mode
予測モードもあります
I am looking for Dr. Hong Yingshan, my classmate from the Meteorological Bureau
気象庁の同級生、ホン・インシャン博士を探しています
Then he himself has the model used by the Meteorological Bureau
そして気象庁が使用した模型を彼自身が持っている。
private weather company
民間気象会社
They are also very interested in our WBGT
彼らは私たちのWBGTにも非常に興味を持っています
They are also willing to initiate
彼らも喜んで始めます
give us a forecast
予測を教えてください
So we have three different patterns
ということで3パターンあります
But the data we've presented so far is one of those patterns
しかし、これまでに紹介したデータはそのパターンの 1 つです。
we are
私たちです
Their model data predictions give me
彼らのモデル データの予測では、
It is forecasting 48 hours data to me
48時間分のデータを予測しています
Then we tested locally
次にローカルでテストしました
After WBGT
WBGT後
Let's compare it with his model
彼のモデルと比較してみましょう
In fact, compared
実際に比べてみると、
In fact, the correlation is quite high
実は相関関係はかなり高い
0.94
０。９４
words from our WI
私たちのWIからの言葉
For example, it is 0.98
たとえば、0.98です。
is also very good
もとても良いです
so i think
だから私は思う
In the future, we will continue to discuss with the Meteorological Bureau
今後、気象庁と協議を続けてまいります。
That is to say, we can actually use existing models to make forecasts
つまり、実際に既存のモデルを使用して予測を行うことができます。
Of course I know the weather bureau is more cautious
もちろん、気象庁がより慎重であることは知っています
It needs to have accumulated enough data
十分なデータを蓄積する必要がある
we are now too
私たちも今です
provides a lot of information
多くの情報を提供します
The proof hopefully will convince it
証拠があれば納得してもらえるだろう
So this is in the schema section
これはスキーマセクションにあります
We test in the community
コミュニティでテストします
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
We can use the local meteorological survey
地元の気象調査を利用できます
to convert
変換する
His local survey
彼の現地調査
In this view the harm index WBGT
このビューでは、危害指数 WBGT
We also do measurements at altitude
高度での測定も行います
more than three floors
3階以上
We have a thin trail above the ground
地面の上に細い道があります
Or do it on the red brick road
それとも赤レンガの道でやるか
then we can take a look
それなら見てみましょう
In fact, this WBGT
実はこのWBGT、
the ground layer that we humans actually walk on
私たち人間が実際に歩く地層
It is on average better than
平均して以下より優れています
WBGT of nearby Meteorological Bureau stations
近隣の気象庁観測所のWBGT
1.5 degrees higher on average
平均1.5度高い
OK
OK
But correlation is good
でも相性はいいですよ
0.7
０。７
So I also talked to Qishang School
そこで旗上学校にも相談しました
In the future, if you predict
今後予想すると
In fact, at least our
実際、少なくとも私たちの
70% of this
このうち 70%
Credibility
信頼性
that is
あれは
you just said you can believe it
あなたは信じられると言ったばかりです
then we are here with you
それなら私たちはあなたと一緒にここにいます
We only need to take this data from your forecast
あなたの予測からこのデータを取得するだけで済みます
because it predicts
それは予測するから
It's probably data from weather stations.
おそらく気象観測所からのデータでしょう。
We add 1.5 degrees C
1.5℃を加えます
Basically we are walking on a normal thin path
基本的には普通の細い道を歩いています
say actual heat hazard
実際の熱の危険性を言う
That'll be fine
それでいいよ
Take a look, the maximum value we measured on the ground floor is actually as high as 41
見てください、1 階で測定した最大値は実際には 41 にも達しました。
We are already in the black period just on 32.2
ちょうど32.2ですでに黒字期に入っています。
But we actually measured it to be 41
でも実際に測ってみると41でした
Of course no one will walk on Boyue Road for 8 hours
もちろん博月路を8時間も歩く人はいないでしょう。
I hope not, so I hope no one will keep saying
そうならないことを願っています、だから誰も言い続けないことを願っています
Spit into such a large high value
こんなに大きな高い値を吐き出す
We are actually estimating, and we use this to calculate
実際に見積もりを行っており、これを使用して計算します。
This Taipei City, because Taipei City is a basin
この台北市、台北市は盆地なので
It is easier to gather heat and not easy to dissipate
熱が集まりやすく放熱しにくい
Therefore, Taipei City is usually the place with the highest temperature in Taiwan.
したがって、通常、台湾で最も気温が高い場所は台北市です。
It’s not that Kaohsiung is quite windy, so it’s actually Taipei
高雄は風が強いわけではないので、実際は台北です
So we look at Taipei City from 2002 to 2016
そこで、2002 年から 2016 年までの台北市を見てみましょう。
In the past 15 years, the maximum value of WBGT on the same day exceeded 32.2 days
過去15年間で同日のWBGTの最大値は32.2日を超えた
How many days?
何日？
more than 1000 days
1000日以上
OK
OK
it is in the summer half
夏も半分です
Let us suppose
仮定してみましょう
I think Taiwan is now only tantamount to saying
台湾は今こう言っているに等しいと思う。
Two seasons of winter
冬の二つの季節
In fact, even winter is full of heat
実は冬でも暑いんです
Summer half year is from May to October
夏の半年間は5月から10月まで
If we only count the half year
半年だけ数えてみると
It actually accounted for 37% of the more than 1,000 days
実際には、1,000 日以上のうち 37% を占めていました。
it's impressive
それは印象的です
means to say
言う意味
throughout the second half of the year
今年の後半を通して
more than a third of the time
3分の1以上の時間
In fact, every day exceeds this
実際には毎日これを超えています
We consider thermal hazards
熱による危険性を考慮します
more severe days
さらに厳しい日々
then such a situation
それからそのような状況
among us feel
私たちの間では感じます
If there is timely warning data
タイムリーな警報データがある場合
how good is it
どれくらい良いですか
like this
このような
people will know
人々は知るでしょう
it's too hot outside now
今外は暑すぎます
I don't want to go out
外出したくない
or me the athlete
あるいはアスリートの私
half training says
半分のトレーニングは言う
we better come back now
今すぐ戻ったほうがいいです
don't train outside
外でトレーニングしないでください
But because now the Meteorological Bureau
でも今は気象庁が
Even if we convert his kitchen
彼のキッチンを改造したにもかかわらず
But the Meteorological Bureau is now on the Internet
しかし、気象庁は今ではインターネット上にあります
this timely
このタイムリーな
Timely data on the website
ウェブサイト上のタイムリーなデータ
With temperature, humidity and wind speed
温度、湿度、風速で
But it doesn't have this timely
でもこれはタイムリーじゃない
Information about solar radiation
日射量に関する情報
OK so
はい、それでは
Our dating house
私たちのデートハウス
Our team is in the whole province
私たちのチームは州全体にいます
From this 2016
この2016年から
It has been established since last year
昨年から新設されました
15 successively established
15件連続設立
Outdoor Seven Observatory
アウトドアセブン展望台
OK we just want to put this
OK、これを入れたいだけです
Radiation data can be disseminated in time
放射線データを適時に配布できる
Then we can calculate
それから計算できます
This WBGT in time
このWBGTは間に合います
OK last year it was
そうですね、去年はそうでした
hottest year hottest year ever
最も暑い年 史上最も暑い年
In Taiwan, it is
台湾では、
If WBGT is calculated, it is July
WBGTを計算すると7月
This is when the WBG is the highest
WBGが最も高くなる時期です
that july
那7月
July 28 is the highest day of WBG
7月28日はWBGの最高日です
OK, let's see for a couple of days
わかりました、数日様子を見ましょう
The whole month of July last year followed
昨年の7月全体が続いた
This July 28th
今年の7月28日
This WBG distribution map
このWBG分布図
Our calculations are based on 12 hours in the daytime.
私たちの計算は日中 12 時間に基づいています。
The one on the left is the average of 12 hours of daylight in the whole month of July
左側は、7 月全体の日照時間の平均 12 時間です。
Then we also see that there are a few black spots here
ここにも黒い点がいくつかあることがわかります
ok Momotsuki wait for this
はい、桃月さん待っててね
Those two black dots
あの二つの黒い点は
It's still going on for a whole month
まだ一ヶ月も続いてるよ
This average is as high as 32.2
この平均は 32.2 にもなります。
So these two are probably due to the terrain
したがって、これら 2 つはおそらく地形によるものです
The wind speed is relatively low or this
風速が比較的低いかこれ
Factors such as relatively high rock and soil will cause this
比較的高い岩や土壌などの要因が原因で発生します。
This is actually a social welfare unit or a labor unit.
これは実際には社会福祉単位または労働単位です。
The key point to pay attention to in the future
今後の注目すべきポイント
that was on july 28th
それは7月28日のことでした
Full water has more can daytime 12 hour average
満水の場合は日中12時間平均でさらに多くの水を摂取できます
Belong to this more than 32.2
32.2以上はこれに属する
ok, that part of Taoyuan, Taozhuniao
わかりました、桃園のその部分、桃竹ニャオ
Then the following words are this
では次の言葉はこれです
Kaohsiung and Pingtung also have some
高雄や屏東にもいくつかあります
The thing that surprised me the most was actually
実は一番驚いたのは、
first place ok first place
第一名ok 第一名
Obviously it is Yonghe District in New Taipei City
明らかに新北市の永和区です
OK
OK
Because I myself grew up forever
私自身が永遠に成長したから
i can't believe our yong ho will win the championship
うちのヨンホが優勝するなんて信じられない
It's actually 33.5 degrees during the day
日中は33.5度くらいあります
after i know this
これを知った後
I will tell my mother
母に言います
Because my mother is in the group that does not turn on the air conditioner at home
母は家ではエアコンをつけない派なので
Because she also thinks she is used to it
彼女も慣れていると思っているので
She washes her face and it's fine
彼女は顔を洗います、それで大丈夫です
So I just told her please please later
だから私は彼女に「後でお願いします」と言いました
We have already won the first place in the province in this matter.
この件に関してはすでに県内で1位を獲得しています。
OK, in the future, you must turn on the air conditioner, what do you want?
はい、今後はエアコンをつけなければなりませんが、どうしますか?
Fortunately, she believed me this year
幸いなことに、彼女は今年私を信じてくれました
This year, at 12:00 noon every day
今年は毎日正午に
she will drive for an hour
彼女は一時間運転するつもりです
then tell me it's nice
それなら素敵だと言ってください
One hour can measure four hours
1 時間で 4 時間を測定できます
OK
OK
So at least I don't have to worry about her this year.
だから少なくとも今年は彼女のことを心配する必要はない。
but this
しかしこれは
Converting this WBGT has this benefit
このWBGTを変換するとこんなメリットがあります
just to help us figure out where it's going to fall
それがどこに落ちるかを理解するのを助けるためだけに
So this labor unit or social welfare unit
つまり、この労働部門または社会福祉部門は
can focus on these villages
これらの村に集中できます
Okay, when we were drawing this picture
さて、この絵を描いているとき
Actually we still have this
実はこれまだあるんです
adjusted in some scientific way
何らかの科学的な方法で調整された
to correct this
これを修正するには
heat island effect
ヒートアイランド現象
We all know that in the city because of the relationship between the buildings
都会では建物と建物の関係性で誰もがそれを知っています
So it creates this heat island effect
それがヒートアイランド現象を引き起こすのです
That is to say, cement and thin oil cannot dissipate after absorbing heat
つまり、セメントや薄い油は熱を吸収した後に放散することができません。
So it's going to be warmer than the usual suburbs next to the suburbs
だから郊外の隣のいつもの郊外よりも暖かくなるでしょう
So we're using the government's numerical terrain model
そこで私たちは政府の数値地形モデルを使用しています
We built the three-dimensional volume of the building with a five-meter resolution
建物の 3 次元ボリュームを 5 メートルの解像度で構築しました
Think of it as a three-dimensional urbanization indicator
3次元の都市化指標として考えてください。
This three-dimensional urbanization index we also go to
この 3 次元都市化指数も参照してください。
Take that and compare it to the temperature distribution on satellite imagery
それを衛星画像の気温分布と比較してください。
In addition, there are more than 30 measuring stations of the Meteorological Bureau in Taipei City.
また、台北市内には気象局の観測所が30カ所以上あります。
its ground station
その地上局
Then do the correlation
次に、相関関係を実行します
Its correlation is very high
その相関性は非常に高いです
Therefore, the three-dimensional urbanization index is also a good indicator to look at the temperature distribution.
したがって、三次元都市化指数も気温分布を見るのに適した指標となります。
But I built another biggest purpose is to
しかし、私が構築したもう一つの最大の目的は、
I hope it's for urban planners to see
都市計画者に見てほしい
So if everyone here
それで、ここにいる全員が
If someone is doing urban planning
誰かが都市計画をやっているとしたら
Because always prevent residual treatment
常に残留処理を防ぐため
OK, we're still working hard to build a house
はい、私たちはまだ家を建てるために頑張っています
And it's covered with cement
そしてこのセメントを覆うのです
This house is reinforced concrete
この家は鉄筋コンクリート造です
So every house built
だから、どの家も建てられる
In fact we just add this
実際にはこれを追加するだけです
The volume of this three-dimensional building
この立体的な建物のボリュームは
Unless they can find some heat sink
ヒートシンクが見つからない限り
compare this
これを比較してください
The materials of these buildings that are not so tall
それほど高くないこれらの建物の材料
Otherwise they are all increasing our thermal conductivity
そうしないと、それらはすべて熱伝導率を増加させます
and adding weight to this under our climate change
そして気候変動の下でこれにさらに重みが加わります
warming shock
温暖化ショック
OK
OK
So I think this thing should be reminded of this
だから、このことは覚えておくべきだと思う
urban planner
都市計画
OK, let's take a look again.
さて、もう一度見てみましょう。
In fact, everyone feels that the weather is very hot this time.
実際、今回の天気はとても暑いと誰もが感じています。
OK
OK
so this was a few days ago
それで、これは数日前のことです
Last week, July 19th
先週、7月19日
12:00 noon to 1:00 pm
正午12時から午後1時まで
this hour
この時間
Let's take back the temperature from the weather bureau
気象庁から気温を取り戻しましょう
its geographical distribution
その地理的分布
Then we also use our
それから私たちも使います
Traditional Radiation Information
従来の放射線情報
We ourselves use
私たち自身も使っています
The Meteorological Bureau has a total of more than 300 stations for temperature, humidity and wind speed
気象局には合計 300 以上の温度、湿度、風速を測定する観測所があります。
plus our own radiation data
加えて私たち独自の放射線データ
We can quickly calculate this WBGT
この WBGT はすぐに計算できます
We can look at its distribution
その分布を見ることができます
Indeed something is different
確かに何かが違う
Especially in some of the more important hotspot areas
特に重要なホットスポット地域の一部では
WBGT because it considers more
WBGT はより多くのことを考慮しているため
And the more important parameters related to physiology
そして、生理機能に関連するより重要なパラメータ
So it can identify more detailed
より詳細な識別ができるようになります
Some important black spots
いくつかの重要な黒い点
black area
黒い領域
These exceed WBGT
これらはWBGTを超えています
These areas are beyond the black area
これらの領域は黒い領域を超えています
This is our afterthought
これは私たちの思いつきです
The data is recovered and drawn with GIS
データは GIS で取得および描画されます
The best paintings are those that can be drawn in time
最高の絵とは、時間内に描くことができるものである
Now we are also cooperating with Teacher Chen from the Information Office
現在、情報局のチェン先生にも協力していただいています。
We are available online in real time
オンラインでリアルタイムに対応可能です
First present these temperature data from the Meteorological Bureau
まずは気象庁からの気温データを提示してください
And the temperature data of our own 15 stations
自社15観測点の温度データと
and add it to our radiation profile
それを放射線プロファイルに追加します
Convert to WBGT
WBGTに変換
So this is the data at 1:30 pm on July 20
これは7月20日午後1時30分のデータです
You can see many places
たくさんの場所が見えます
In fact, many places in the western half are black chess
実際、西半分の多くの場所は黒チェスです
There is only one area in the middle
真ん中に一箇所だけエリアがある
It's because of the cloud and the relatively strong wind speed.
雲があり、風速が比較的強いためです。
So the temperature drops faster
そのため気温が早く下がります
The north side too
北側も
On the Danshui side, because the wind blows
風が吹くので淡水側へ
So it goes down faster
だから下がるのが早いんだよ
What about the black chess
黒のチェスはどうですか
lasts until 4 p.m.
午後4時まで続く
OK, it lasted so long
OK、それはとても長く続きました
OK, so in fact we're observing this immediate
OK、実際に私たちはこの瞬間を観察しています
Sometimes it is found that there is a thermal hazard
場合によっては熱による危険性があることが判明する
Black's words will continue until 6:00 p.m.
ブラックの言葉は午後6時まで続く。
OK, this is
OK、これは
especially in this
特にこれでは
Special attention should be paid to those who work outside the office
オフィス外で働く人は特に注意が必要です
then we also want
それなら私たちも欲しいです
In the future, we can cooperate with the Meteorological Bureau in this regard.
今後は気象庁とも協力していきたいと思います。
be able to take the data we've built
私たちが構築したデータを取得できる
available to the Bureau of Meteorology
気象庁が入手可能
This WBGT warning can be issued in the future
この WBGT 警告は将来発行される可能性があります
with this instant observation
この一瞬の観察で
Currently the Taipei City Environmental Protection Bureau is very interested in
現在、台北市環境保護局は以下のことに非常に興味を持っています。
We are currently cooperating with the Taipei City Environmental Protection Bureau
現在、台北市環境保護局と協力しています。
It is hoped that the system of Relujing in Taipei City can be established
台北市にレルジンのシステムが確立されることを願っています
So let's look at that day
それでは、その日の様子を見てみましょう
At 1:30 p.m. on July 21
7月21日午後1時30分頃
The whole city of Taipei is black
台北の街全体が真っ黒です
Because Taipei City is not easy to dissipate heat
台北市は熱を逃がしにくいため
is a basin center
盆地中心です
Only Yangmingshan is slightly more comfortable
陽明山だけはもう少し快適です
Look at the white in the middle
真ん中の白い部分を見てください
says it has no data
データがないことを意味します
Because we follow the weather station
私たちは気象観測所に従っているので
Draw a circle if its diameter is within 5 kilometers
直径が5km以内であれば円を描きます
So there are missing values ​​in some places
そのため、いくつかの場所に欠損値があります
In the future, we hope that
将来的には、
Real-time prediction of thermal hazards for the Taipei area
台北地域の熱災害のリアルタイム予測
Currently cooperating with Taipei Environmental Protection Bureau
現在、台北市環境保護局と協力中
In fact, we are on top of the earth lock of Academia Sinica
実際、私たちは中央研究院の地球錠の上にいます。
There is a weather station that we set up
私たちが設置した気象観測所があります
We originally wanted to set it up on the roof of the Japan Ministry
当初は外務省の屋上に設置したかった
However, there are too many outlets of air conditioners on the roof of the Japanese department, which will affect our data
ただし、日本部門の屋上にはエアコンの吹き出し口が多すぎるため、データに影響します。
So it was not set there
したがって、そこには設定されていませんでした
We are in Taipei except for the stop of Zhongyingyuan
私たちは中営源の停留所を除いて台北にいます
We also have four other stations
他にも4つの駅があります
It was done for the Taipei City Environmental Protection Bureau
台北市環境保護局のために行われました。
So we also analyzed the historical data of Taipei City
そこで、台北市の歴史データも分析しました。
last 15 years
過去15年間
If we only look at May to October
5月から10月だけで見ると
We look at the highest WBGT of the United States and Japan
アメリカと日本の最高WBGTを見てみる
On which level of thermal hazard would it be distributed
熱的危険性のどのレベルに分布するか
From the perspective of 2016
2016年の視点から
There are actually 103 days
実際には103日あります
It's more than half the time it's on black paint
半分以上が黒いペイントの上に落ちます
this is serious
これは深刻です
So everyone don't want to say
だからみんな言いたくないんだよ
What price can be placed above 32.2 degrees
32.2度を超えるとどのくらいの価格を設定できますか
it's impossible
それは不可能だ
Because this is the norm for us
それが私たちにとって当たり前のことだから
But we can indeed remind you
しかし、私たちは確かにあなたに思い出させることができます
at this time
現時点では
For example, children should not go outside
たとえば、子供たちは外に出てはいけない
Or athletes marked outside training
または、トレーニング外でマークされたアスリート
or how outdoor workers protect themselves
または屋外労働者がどのように身を守るか
If we take this
これを取ると
The 99th percentile of the daily maximum temperature for the past 15 years
過去 15 年間の日最高気温の 99 パーセンタイル
That is 36.8%
つまり 36.8%
If used as another level of classification
別のレベルの分類として使用される場合
we are one more level
私たちはもう一つのレベルです
The hottest year in 2016 last year
昨年2016年は最も暑かった年
about 5 days
約5日間
would be this higher than this 36.8%
これより高いだろうか 36.8%
so it's possible
だからそれは可能です
We are still discussing with the Taipei City Environmental Protection Bureau
台北市環境保護局と協議中です。
say it's possible
可能だと言う
if you really want to post this
本当にこれを投稿したい場合は
In other words, I suggest that everyone should not go out.
言い換えれば、皆さんは外出しないでくださいと提案します。
It is possible that the relatively high temperature
比較的高温になっている可能性があります
as this pre-value
この事前値として
Of course such discussions
もちろんそういう議論も
There's a lot behind this
この裏にはたくさんのことがあります
science we have to try our best
科学、私たちは最善を尽くさなければなりません
including our statistics institute
私たちの統計研究所も含めて
Teacher Huang Jingxiang is cooperating
黄京祥先生が協力しています
just look at this
これを見てください
Use health insurance data to analyze
健康保険データを活用した分析
this some health
これはある程度の健康
healthy data
健全なデータ
We based on the past 2000 to 2014
過去2000年から2014年までをベースにしています
Including the number of emergency visits, the number of old visits or
緊急訪問の数、古い訪問の数、または
The number of deaths after 2008 The number of deaths from all causes
2008年以降の死亡者数 全死因による死亡者数
We can currently see about 32.5 degrees or more
現在約32.5度以上が見られます
WBGT32.5 degrees or more
WBGT32.5度以上
Or above 33 degrees, it is a sharp rise
33度を超えると急激に上昇します
As for this part, we are still working on it.
この部分に関しては、現在も開発中です。
But that's pretty much it
しかし、それはほとんどそれだけです
The relevant information is quite consistent.
関連情報は非常に一貫しています。
Next, we also see another
次に、別のものも見てみましょう
The high-risk group we just kept mentioning
先ほど言い続けた高リスクグループ
It means working outdoors, especially construction workers
屋外で働くこと、特に建設労働者を意味します
It is dried by this long-term shop
こちらの長期店で乾燥されています
This is a person who works on site to block steel bars
現場で鉄筋をブロックする作業をしている人です
This is the Labor Safety Office of the Labor Council
こちらは労働審議会労働安全室です
labor safety office
労働安全局
They know we're doing this outdoor WBGT
彼らは私たちがこの屋外 WBGT を行っていることを知っています
So they also come to cooperate with us
それで彼らも私たちに協力してくれるようになりました
Then last year, we found five long-term jobs
そして昨年、5件の長期雇用の仕事を見つけました。
Let’s take a look at the actual process of labor that we have seen in the five long-term jobs
5つの長期勤務で見てきた労働の実際のプロセスを見てみましょう
work situation
仕事の状況
This one is in Banggang
これは方崗井にあります
Then this word is doing this template
この単語はこのテンプレートを実行しています
It has this cement in it
このセメントが入ってます
have this plank
この板を持っています
These are heat-absorbing materials
これらは熱を吸収する素材です
ok
Ok
Then this is doing electric welding
続いて電気溶接を行っていきます
and next to it is a surfboard
そしてその隣にはサーフボードがあります
tree with surf boards reflecting sunlight
日光を反射するサーフボードのある木
also very dazzling very hot
とても眩しい、とても暑い
The electric welding is also a very hot
電気溶接も非常に熱いです
So they are in the workplace
それで彼らは職場にいる
There are a lot of things that are
ということがたくさんあります
within a meter of them
彼らから1メートル以内
They will have accumulated high temperature
高温が蓄積されているでしょう
so they are exposed to thermal hazards
そのため熱の危険にさらされます
Probably very different 10 meters away
おそらく10メートル離れたらかなり違うでしょう
ok
Ok
so what about this
それで、これはどうですか
That's why Labor Bran
だからこそ労働ブラン
He hopes to develop a wearable device
彼はウェアラブルデバイスを開発したいと考えています
Therefore, Mr. Chen Yanzhi of our information center
そこで、弊社インフォメーションセンターのChen Yanzhi氏は、
Also use a small one for them
小さいものも使用してください
Sensing of miniature temperature, humidity, etc.
小型の温度、湿度などをセンシング
go get a small one like an orange bag
オレンジ色のバッグのような小さなものを取りに行きます
Tied to this waist of labor
この労働の腰に縛られて
so these words
だからこれらの言葉は
help us to tie this orange bag
このオレンジ色の袋を結ぶのを手伝ってください
let's see
どれどれ
like this
このような
I admire this pre-resident worker the most
私はこの前駐在員を最も尊敬します
He's going to stand on that pre-dwelling steel girder
彼はその建設前の鉄骨の上に立つことになる
Because he wants to direct where the two pre-occupied pillars will fall
なぜなら、彼は、優先される 2 本の柱がどこに落ちるかを指示したいからです。
Once he stood there, he couldn't get down for two or three hours.
一度そこに立ってしまうと、2、3時間は降りることができなかった。
OK
OK
Then I want to say that when I went to this construction site at seven o'clock in the morning
それから私が言いたいのは、朝7時にこの建設現場に行ったときのことです。
I have already sunned into this big Hanlin
私はすでにこの大きな翰林に日光浴しました
Then he will stand there for two or three hours
それから彼はそこに2、3時間立っているでしょう
really hard
とても大変
The director of the construction site told us that
工事現場の監督さんはこう言いました。
don't be afraid
恐れないでください
They are heat acclimatized
彼らは暑さに順応しています
They've been doing this for so long
彼らはこれを長い間やっています
none of them matter
どれも重要ではない
That's what these laborers told us
それが労働者たちが私たちに語った言葉です
He said they were used to it
彼らはそれに慣れていると彼は言いました
OK
OK
But Tian Wenjun also told us at the same time
しかし、ティアン・ウェンジュンも同時に私たちに言いました。
In fact, more than half of them have this kind of experience
実は半数以上の人がこのような経験をしています。
It's just that none of them seek medical attention
ただ、誰も医師の診察を受けていないだけです
just drink more water
もっと水を飲んでください
Then just rest there
それならそこで休んでください
OK
OK
So although these are for us
ですから、これらは私たちのためのものではありますが、
maybe not
そうでないかもしれない
This is the ethnic group with high ranks
これは高位の民族です
so they may be fit and healthy
彼らが元気で健康でいられるように
not what we usually say
私たちが普段言っていることではありません
This community that seems so sensitive and fragile
とても繊細で壊れやすいこのコミュニティ
But think about these strong and strong people
しかし、これらの強くて強い人々のことを考えてください
Maybe it's the spirit of the family
それは家族の精神なのかもしれない
the backbone of the economy
経済の根幹
in case of falling down
転倒した場合に備えて
Most likely a whole family is broken
おそらく家族全員が崩壊している
So the Ministry of Labor knows this very well.
ですから、労働省はそれをよく知っています。
So the current word is hope to say
だから今の言葉は希望です
There is this wearable this
こんなウェアラブルもあるよ
Thermometric Hazards
温度測定による危険性
Then the data can be transmitted to the back-end platform
その後、データをバックエンド プラットフォームに送信できます。
What about this platform?
このプラットフォームについてはどうですか?
Can let the site supervisor see
現場監督に見てもらうことができる
so they can do this time shift
彼らはこのタイムシフトを行うことができます
just don't let the same person
同じ人にはさせないでください
Do a frequent exposure to high temperature thermal hazards
高温の熱的危険に頻繁にさらされる
this is too serious
これは深刻すぎる
So if his way of working hours is allocated
したがって、彼の勤務時間が割り当てられている場合、
reduce the heat hazard
熱の危険を減らす
OK
OK
over here
ここに
Everyone has seen that there is a
があることは誰もが見たことがあります。
goats
ヤギ
are you happy
幸せですか
It's just that someone is finally going to break up these laborers
ただ、ついに誰かがこの労働者たちを解体しようとしているだけだ
No, I lied to you
いいえ、私はあなたに嘘をつきました
good self-deception
良い自己欺瞞
It's true that there were breakups at the construction site
建設現場で解散があったのは事実だ
but not for labor
しかし労働のためではない
OK
OK
It's an underground archaeological site
地下遺跡です
OK he was actually trying to prevent this
OK、彼は実際にこれを阻止しようとしていた
Archaeological artifacts scattered by sun-baked camps
太陽が照りつける収容所に散らばる考古学的遺物
In fact, the bottom line
実際、肝心なのは
Because of the dispersion, it is more stuffy
分散しているのでさらに蒸れやすい
OK so actually
わかりました、実際のところ
In fact, this is both good and bad.
実際、これは良いことでもあり、悪いことでもあります。
Then when we actually do it on the spot
では、実際に現場でやってみると、
Except this worker has this wearable
この従業員がこのウェアラブルを持っていることを除いて
We also have this on site with this mobile weather observer
また、この移動式気象観測装置を現場に設置しています。
Because some laborers
労働者もいるから
It's inconvenient to have these devices on your body
これらの機器を体に装着すると不便です
So let's also try
じゃあ、私も試してみましょう
Look, if there is a mobile weather observer
ほら、移動気象観測員がいるなら
Is it possible to explain them this too?
これについても説明することは可能でしょうか？
Measure roughly
おおよその寸法を測る
they may be exposed to heat hazards
熱の危険にさらされる可能性があります
Let's also compare it with the battle of the Meteorological Bureau, which is one or two kilometers away.
１、２キロ離れた気象庁の戦いとも比べてみましょう。
Here is our data
これが私たちのデータです
Let's take a look, this is actually
見てみましょう、これは実際にあります
A time sequence from nine o'clock in the morning until the afternoon when you get off work
朝の9時から仕事が終わる午後までの時系列
ok
Ok
What about these red lines are these five different workers
この赤い線は何ですか、これら 5 人の異なる労働者は何ですか?
Five different workers each day
毎日5人の異なる労働者
ok
Ok
That blue, dark blue line is the mobile meteorological instrument we have on site
その青、濃い青の線は、私たちが現場に設置している移動式気象計器です。
And the blue line is the weather station of the Meteorological Bureau that is farther away.
そして青線はさらに離れたところにある気象庁測候所です。
It's obvious here
ここで明らかです
Apparently seeing the weather station, the temperature of labor timing may be five or six degrees worse
明らかに気象観測所を見ると、出産時期の気温は5〜6度悪くなる可能性があります
Even the blue people on the scene may sometimes be two or three degrees off
現場にいる青い人たちでさえ、時々 2 度か 3 度ずれることがある
It means that the promotion of workers is actually affected by many reflections, whether it is heat-absorbing steel bars, cement, wood boards or corrugated boards.
熱線吸収鉄筋であれ、セメントであれ、木板であれ、段ボールであれ、多くの反射が実は労働者の昇進に影響を与えているということです。
Let me show you again. We know that the black flag is 32.2. There is a black flag drawn here.
もう一度お見せします。黒旗は 32.2 であることがわかります。ここに黒旗が描かれています。
So most of the time here is actually in the afternoon because of the heavy thunderstorm, so everyone went on vacation
激しい雷雨のため、ここにいる時間は午後になることがほとんどなので、みんな休暇に出かけました。
During thunderstorms, the construction industry cannot work for fear of danger, so there is no work for this matter.
雷雨の時は、建設業は危険を恐れて仕事ができないので、この件に関しては仕事がありません。
But under other circumstances, you can see that most of their time, working time may be more than 65%
しかし、他の状況では、ほとんどの時間、労働時間は 65% を超える可能性があることがわかります。
All of them are under the status of WPGT is black flag, so it shows the situation of their industry
それらはすべてWPGTが黒旗のステータスにあるため、業界の状況を示しています
Gao Shou's siege of flesh is actually quite serious.
Gao Shou の肉の包囲は実際にはかなり深刻です。
But we asked the worker
しかし、私たちはこの労働者に尋ねました。
Workers don't really want a holiday
労働者は本当は休日を望んでいない
because they are everyday
それらは毎日のことだから
Profitable
儲かる
He only makes a day's money for every day he works
彼は毎日働いても一日分のお金しか稼げない
so he has no interest in vacation
だから彼は休暇に興味がない
what do they want
彼らは何を望んでいるのか
They want it to be like the Law Enforcement Office
彼らはそれを法執行機関のようにしたいと考えている
That is, if someone moves it or arranges it during working hours
つまり、誰かが勤務時間中に移動したり整理したりした場合
or even they some employers are better
あるいは、雇用主の方が優れている場合もあります
That is, from 12:00 noon to 3:00 p.m., there is no need to do anything
つまり、正午から午後3時までは何もする必要はありません。
He just rests but he gets off work late
彼はただ休んでいるだけですが、仕事を終えるのが遅くなります
they would like to do it like this
彼らはこのようにしたいと思っています
So they also reduce their own meat damage
したがって、彼らは自分自身の肉へのダメージも軽減します
Then it won't affect their money making
そうすれば彼らの金儲けには影響しない
This is a win-win situation
これは双方にとって有利な状況です
everyone can see say
誰もが見ることができます
when we measure
測定するとき
In fact, it can also be clearly seen
実はこれもはっきりと確認できます
Sometimes they go to blow the air conditioner
時々エアコンを吹きに行きます
during lunch break
昼休み中に
There will be this red line that is down and down
この赤い線がずっと続いています
Said that they were lucky to have a real rest during their lunch break
昼休みにしっかり休めたのは幸運だったと言っていました
This is the real situation in the labor workplace
これが労働現場の現実です
So let's talk about this regression
それではこの回帰について話しましょう
We explore the vulnerability of this thermal hazard
この熱的危険性の脆弱性を調査します
I just talked a lot about measuring WBGT
WBGTの測定についてたくさんお話しました
If we look at it in July 2013
2013年7月を見てみると
Probably the highest in Taipei
おそらく台北で一番高い
Then we divide into 7 equal parts
次に、7等分します
The red word means it is the most serious
赤い文字は最も深刻であることを意味します
The northern part is the same as the Taichung area
北部は台中エリアと同じ
Possibly the highest WBGT
おそらく最高のWBGT
In terms of sensitivity
感度の面では
In fact, the proportion of the elderly population is relatively high
実は高齢者人口の割合が比較的高いのです
The population of young children is relatively high
幼児人口が比較的多い
like this Huadong area
この花東地区のように
so it's red
だから赤いよ
that they are the most sensitive
彼らは最も敏感であるということ
Then we also consider the existing
次に、既存のものも考慮します
Cardiovascular disease visits
心血管疾患の訪問
we also took it into consideration
私たちもそれを考慮しました
to draw this sensitivity map
この感度マップを描くには
In terms of shadow ability
影の能力に関しては
We consider the community's
私たちはコミュニティのことを考慮します
its this medical resource
この医療リソースです
The ratio of their air conditioner
エアコンの割合
and his community
そして彼のコミュニティ
this society
この社会
It should say community development association, etc.
まちづくり協会等と言うべきでしょうか。
The number of these social organizations
これらの社会組織の数
Then draw this map
それからこの地図を描いてください
Everyone can take a look
誰でも見ることができます
In fact, the central region
実は中部地方は
ok even
大丈夫です
In the area of ​​Ganan
加南エリア
Response ability is relatively weak
対応力が比較的弱い
so red is the worst
だから赤は最悪だ
Okay, let's combine these three dimensions
さて、これら 3 つの次元を組み合わせてみましょう
You can draw the whole of Taiwan
台湾全体を描くことができます
This map of vulnerability to thermal hazards
熱的危険に対する脆弱性のこのマップ
It can also be clearly seen here
ここでもはっきりとわかります
Although the northern region
北部地域ですが、
It seems that the risk is higher
リスクのほうが高い気がする
But because of the strong response ability
しかし、対応力が強いので
The characteristics of the population are also less sensitive
集団の特徴もあまり敏感ではない
So it's actually only a few
なので実際はほんの数個です
A place with a relatively high population
比較的人口の多い場所
belong to the sixth level of high vulnerability
高い脆弱性の第 6 レベルに属します
Others are fine
他は大丈夫です
central words
中心的な言葉
Instead it is because
むしろ、それは、
Central and Yoga South
セントラルとヨガサウス
Possibly a relationship of lower coping capacity
おそらく対処能力が低い関係
So the vulnerability is higher
したがって脆弱性はより高くなります
Next is the part of Pingtung
次は屏東編です
Taitung Night Market
台東夜市
Of course, this vulnerability will change with the change of society.
もちろん、この脆弱性は社会の変化とともに変化します。
including population changes
人口変動も含めて
Changes in social conditions
社会情勢の変化
with us this
私たちと一緒にこれ
Changes in the risk situation environment
リスク状況環境の変化
So this is actually a rolling
これは実際にはローリングです
can be modified in the map
マップ内で変更できます
If our government has a good countermeasure
私たちの政府が良い対抗策を持っていれば
We can also use this vulnerability map to see
この脆弱性マップを使用して確認することもできます。
So his coping strategy
それで彼の対処戦略は
Does it help various regions after implementation
導入後はさまざまな地域に役立つか
to reduce their vulnerability
彼らの脆弱性を軽減するために
That's what vulnerability maps are for
それが脆弱性マップの目的です
So what we just mentioned is
それで、私たちが今述べたことは、
Vulnerability to this thermal hazard
この熱的危険に対する脆弱性
straight up climate change
まさに気候変動
How to impact our sensitive community
デリケートなコミュニティに影響を与える方法
its exposure, its response
その暴露とその反応
However, in addition to the direct impact
しかし、直接的な影響に加えて、
There is also an indirect pathway of influence
間接的な影響経路もある
That is by affecting air pollution
それは大気汚染に影響を与えることによるものです
when the temperature is high
気温が高いとき
The volatility of many pollutants is relatively high
多くの汚染物質の揮発性は比較的高い
Its photochemical work is also relatively strong
光化学的な働きも比較的強い
Therefore, there are more pollutants in production and survival
したがって、生産と生存にはより多くの汚染物質が存在します。
and some are
そしていくつかは
when the temperature is high
気温が高いとき
sometimes it's this
時々それはこれです
The conditions for domineering diffusion are bad
横暴な拡散の条件が悪い
For example, there was this high pressure a few days ago
たとえば、数日前にこのような高気圧がありました
hot high pressure
熱い高圧
High pressure is equivalent to
高圧は以下に相当します。
There is a cover on it
その上にカバーが付いています
OK submerged layer
OK 水没層
So there is this submerged layer phenomenon
つまり、この水没層現象が存在するのです
Therefore, air pollutants are not easy to diffuse out.
したがって、大気汚染物質が外部に拡散しにくいのです。
Therefore, the concentration of air pollutants will increase
したがって、大気汚染物質の濃度は増加します
words to people
人への言葉
That is when he is in hot weather at the same time
それは彼が同時に暑い気候にあるときです
subjected to heat stress
熱ストレスにさらされる
Also under pressure from air pollution
大気汚染による圧力も受けている
What about the two pressures?
2つの圧力についてはどうですか？
Affected organs are all heart or lungs
影響を受ける臓器はすべて心臓または肺です
may be cardiopulmonary organs
心肺器官かもしれない
As far as humans are concerned, this is double
人間に関して言えば2倍です
This um affects double pressure
これは二重の圧力に影響します
so we are doing
だから私たちはやっています
thermal vulnerability
熱的脆弱性
Apple also polluted the air at the same time.
アップルは同時に大気も汚染した。
At the same time, the most important words for that are
同時に、そのために最も重要な言葉は、
The pollutant PM2.5
汚染物質PM2.5
this is us
これが私たちです
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
Generally speaking, what kind of interdisciplinary approach do we use
一般的に言えば、どのような学際的なアプローチを使用しますか
And then actually target other than doing this
そして実際にこれを行う以外のターゲットを設定します
In addition to the distribution of this heat hazard in geography
この熱害の地理的分布に加えて、
We actually also targeted air pollutants
実は大気汚染物質もターゲットにしていました
Our purpose is to hope to be able to construct
私たちの目的は、構築できることを望むことです。
Adaptation strategies based on scientific data
科学的データに基づいた適応戦略
That is how to do something better
それが何かをより良くする方法です
Government policies can help us reduce
政府の政策は私たちの削減に役立ちます
The impact and risk to health
健康への影響とリスク
ok so this
わかりました、それではこれ
The results of our first issue after we did
最初の問題を実行した後の結果
Thank you also to the Center for Sustainability for organizing a results presentation
成果発表会を主催してくださった持続可能な開発センターにも感謝します。
We invited representatives from 17 institutions
17機関から代表者を招待しました
covers a lot
たくさんカバーします
including the Department of Health and Welfare like the Bureau of Meteorology
気象局などの保健福祉部を含む
EPA, etc.
EPAなど
We are opening a lot of reps
多くの担当者をオープンしています
are very interested in our research results
私たちの研究結果に非常に興味があります
So there are words like this after the Meteorological Bureau and the Ministry of Health and Welfare
気象庁と厚生省の後にこういう言葉があるわけですね。
They also asked us to continue the meeting
彼らはまた、私たちに会議を継続するよう求めました
see how we can help them
私たちが彼らをどのように助けることができるか見てみましょう
certain relevant policies
特定の関連ポリシー
Like the Taipei City Environmental Protection Bureau and the Ministry of Labor
台北市環境保護局や労働部のように
Later also by the Bureau of Meteorology
その後、気象庁からも
They also suggested that these two units come to us
彼らはまた、この 2 つの部隊が私たちに来ることを提案しました。
to continue to do the next heat hazard effects
次の熱害効果を継続するため
So our policies
したがって、私たちのポリシー
In addition to saying to continue to communicate with these government units
これらの政府機関とのコミュニケーションを継続すると言うことに加えて、
other words
他の言葉
I think it is very important to talk about how we can provide more miscellaneous stones
どうすればより多くの石を提供できるかについて話し合うことが非常に重要だと思います
scientific data
科学的データ
can help them cope better
彼らがより良く対処できるよう助けることができる
That's what we're planning
それが私たちが計画していることです
this purpose
この目的
then this part
それからこの部分
And of course it also includes parts like air pollution
もちろん大気汚染などの部分も含まれます
ok
Ok
Then this is what we do in the community
それから、これが私たちがコミュニティでやっていることです
We just talked about walking and jumping community
先ほどウォーキングとジャンプのコミュニティについて話しました
It's what we've done in the community
それは私たちがコミュニティでやってきたことです
we are at ground level
私たちは地上にいる
good or level
良いまたはレベル
have placed these
これらを置きました
device for sampling or observing
サンプリングまたは観察のための装置
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
with meteorological heat hazards
気象による熱の危険を伴う
Actually other words
実は別の言葉
All are air pollutants
どれも大気汚染物質です
including solarizations like this
このようなソラリゼーションを含む
Here are some precursors of pn2.5
ここにpn2.5の前駆体がいくつかあります
Then pn2.5 still has ergodic distribution
pn2.5 にはまだエルゴディック分布があります
And then there's black charcoal, which is toxic to health
それから黒炭は健康に有害です
And how cold is the direction to listen to this or something like this
で、これとかこれを聴く方向はなんて寒いんだろう。
monitor
モニター
That's just
それはただ
then we still have
それならまだあります
Use this green paper to collect samples for component analysis
この緑色の紙を使用して、成分分析用のサンプルを収集します。
However, these component analyzes take a lot of time to do.
ただし、これらの成分分析には非常に時間がかかります。
this analysis
この分析
So today's words are not
だから今日の言葉はそうではありません
You have a way to report this data to everyone
このデータを全員に報告する方法があります
ok so let's go first
わかりました、それでは最初に行きましょう
look again
もう一度見てください
Our definition of overhang
オーバーハングの定義
Why do we care so much about this so-called pn2.5
なぜ私たちはこのいわゆるpn2.5をそんなに気にするのでしょうか？
ok
Ok
this pn2.5
このpn2.5
PM's words refer to suspension as force
首相の言葉、停止は強制であると言及
PM refers to the force of particle size less than 10 microns
PM とは、粒子サイズが 10 ミクロン未満の力を指します。
We don't care if it is greater than 10
10 より大きいかどうかは気にしません
why
なぜ
Because our nose hairs keep them out
鼻毛が鼻毛の侵入を妨げているからです
So progress greater than 10 comes
したがって、10を超える進歩が得られます
unless
そうでもなければ
unless you run
走らない限り
desperately open mouth to breathe
必死に口を開けて呼吸する
At this time he may come in from your rouge
現時点では、彼はあなたのルージュから入ってくるかもしれません
OK
OK
Otherwise it won't get into your nose
そうしないと鼻に入らないよ
So we don't care if it is greater than 10
したがって、10 を超えているかどうかは気にしません。
from a health point of view
健康の観点から
That
それか
Larger than 10 microns will come in
10ミクロンを超えるものも入ってきます
affects our upper respiratory tract
上気道に影響を与える
but only smaller than 2.5 microns
ただし2.5ミクロンより小さいだけ
can be implanted into our lung cannon
私たちの肺大砲に埋め込むことができる
deep in the lungs
肺の奥深くに
Then it depends on what kind of pollutants he has
それは彼がどのような種類の汚染物質を持っているかによります
what effect will it have on us
それは私たちにどんな影響を与えるでしょうか
He is more able to penetrate our body
彼は私たちの体に浸透することができます
and accumulate over there
そしてそこに溜まる
long-term impact on us as a whole
私たち全体への長期的な影響
that some words are
いくつかの言葉は
This acute irritant
この急性刺激物は、
like acid flu
酸性インフルエンザのように
That's something like listening in the cold direction
それは冷たい方向に聞いているようなものです
He is spontaneous
彼は自発的です
And some if it's heavy metal
ヘヴィメタルの場合もある
he is bad for nerves
彼は神経質です
So he sees what his ingredients are
そこで彼は自分の材料が何であるかを確認します
have different effects on our body
私たちの体にさまざまな影響を及ぼします
This is why I care so much about PN2.5
これが私が PN2.5 をとても気にする理由です
Source words of PN2.5
PN2.5の原語
It's not all man made.
すべて人間が作ったものではありません。
some are of natural origin
一部は天然由来のものです
So that's why the World Health Organization
だからこそ、世界保健機関は
his annual
彼の毎年恒例の
The recommended value for the annual average is 10 meters
年間平均の推奨値は 10 メートルです
per cubic meter
立方メートルあたり
he didn't book zero
彼はゼロを予約しませんでした
because even if no one is there
たとえ誰もそこにいなかったとしても
In fact, nature still has
実は自然界には今でも
Man-made, of course, is factory emissions
もちろん人為的なものは工場からの排出物です
Combustion activities Automobiles etc.
燃焼活動 自動車など
If distinguished by the process of the itinerary
旅程の過程で区別される場合
He can also be divided into
彼は次のように分けることもできます
Suspected pollutants discharged directly from the source
疑わしい汚染物質が発生源から直接排出される
directly from the drain
排水溝から直接
Including factory emissions, automobile and motorcycle emissions
工場からの排出ガス、自動車およびオートバイの排出ガスを含む
Kitchen fumes are directly discharged
厨房の排気ガスを直接排出
some air pollutants
いくつかの大気汚染物質
When discharged, it is a gas
排出するとガスになります
But he has undergone some photochemical reactions
しかし、彼はいくつかの光化学反応を起こしました
after some action
何らかの行動をとった後
The prize of the itinerary
旅程の賞品
This is from the secondary
これは二次からです
We call it secondary pollutant
それを二次汚染物質と呼びます
after some process
何らかのプロセスを経て
Pollutants emitted directly by
から直接排出される汚染物質
becomes an example
例になります
So PL2.5 is so difficult to control
つまり、PL2.5は制御が非常に難しいのです
It is because it has the process of secondary pollutants
二次汚染物質のプロセスがあるからです
So even if we regulate pollutants once
だから一度汚染物質を規制したとしても
We still control many of its precursors
私たちはその前駆体の多くを今でも制御しています
only valid
のみ有効です
Otherwise it keeps generating this
そうしないと、これが生成され続けます
generate this secondary pollutant
この二次汚染物質を生成する
this is our asia
これが私たちのアジアです
But say this is global
しかし、これが世界的なものだと言う
2010 to 2012
2010年から2012年
Three-year global average of this PL2.5
このPL2.5の3年間の世界平均
It can be seen that the Asian region is particularly red
アジア地域が特に赤いことがわかります
Just mentioned the World Health Organization
先ほど世界保健機関について言及しました
The suggested value for the annual average is
年間平均の推奨値は次のとおりです。
Ten Dimensional Meters
十次元メートル
What about the Asian region?
アジア地域はどうですか？
It's possible to get to this 80 to 100
これを80〜100にすることは可能です
What about the three-year average?
3年間の平均はどうでしょうか？
80 to 100 dimension meters
80～100寸法メートル
victor cubic meter
ビクター立方メートル
OK very high
OK 非常的高
Of course it's also because of the Asian region
もちろんアジア地域だからでもありますが
The economy has been booming in recent years
近年経済は好況です
this
これ
and it may be
そしてそれはかもしれない
The control of the factory is not so strict
工場の管理はそれほど厳しくない
What about Taiwan?
台湾はどうですか？
In the case of Taiwan, the Environmental Protection Agency has also made great efforts.
台湾では環境保護局も多大な努力を払っています。
This air pollutant in Taiwan
台湾の大気汚染物質
For example, sulfur dioxide
たとえば、二酸化硫黄
it is also this
それもこれです
A precursor of PN2.5
PN2.5の前身
sulfur dioxide
二酸化硫黄
PN10 or PN2.5
PN10またはPN2.5
In fact, there is a downward trend
実は減少傾向にある
So the EPA is not doing nothing
EPAは何もしていないわけではない
it does a lot of things
それはたくさんのことをします
Only then can such a decline be caused
そうして初めてこのような衰退が引き起こされる可能性がある
But what is everyone unhappy about now?
しかし、みんなは今何に不満を持っているのでしょうか？
not happy
満足していない
because the World Health Organization says
世界保健機関がこう言っているからです
The annual average should be only ten meters
年間平均はわずか10メートルであるはずです
Ten is Kemei local factory
テンはケメイの地元工場です
But we can't come down yet
でもまだ降りることはできない
ok our current words
OK、今の言葉
Probably only the east is barely this
おそらく東だけがギリギリこれ
The average annual
平均年間
just under ten
10弱
Otherwise, it is probably this
そうでなければ、おそらくこれです
3 40
３ ４０
It's even lower in recent years
近年はさらに下がっている
about 2 30
2 30頃
ok
Ok
That's because PN2.5 is considered a human carcinogen by the World Health Organization
それは、PN2.5が世界保健機関によってヒトの発がん物質とみなされているためです。
so words
だから言葉
That's why everyone cares so much
だからみんなすごく気にかけてるんだよ
will hope to be able to lower and lower
どんどん下げられることを願っています
Then let me mention it here
ここで言及させてください
Even after ambient concentrations drop
周囲の濃度が下がった後でも
doesn't mean the front of your nose
鼻の前という意味ではありません
Exposure concentrations dropped below 10 microns
暴露濃度は10ミクロン未満に低下
OK
OK
Because of this exposure concentration
この暴露集中のせいで
It's the concentration in front of my nose
それは私の鼻の前の集中力です
with the one they were testing
彼らがテストしていたものと
10 meters or more
10メートル以上
The EPA's measurements are usually above 10 meters
EPA の測定値は通常 10 メートルを超えています
It measures the uniform mixture of a city
都市の均一な混合を測定します
concentration of air pollutants
大気汚染物質の濃度
Its purpose is to compare
その目的は比較することです
Is Taipei City better this year than last year?
今年の台北市は昨年よりも良いですか?
Or compare it with Taipei City, Taichung, and Kaohsiung this year
あるいは今年の台北市、台中、高雄と比較してみてはいかがでしょうか
which city is better
どの都市が良いですか
do it like this
このようにしてください
so it's all evenly mixed
それですべてが均一に混ざります
in front of our noses
私たちの鼻の前で
Probably especially this one in Asia
おそらくこれはアジアでは特にそうです
In the community we just talked about
先ほど話したコミュニティで
so many different sources of pollution
非常に多くの異なる汚染源
OK
OK
including cars like this one
このような車も含めて
discharge this temple directly
この寺院を直接解放します
Or a small factory in the catering industry, etc.
あるいは外食産業の小さな工場など。
If these are directly discharged
これらが直接排出される場合
will cause us more
もっと私たちに影響を与えるだろう
the exposure concentration
暴露濃度
Exposure density
曝顯濃度
Let's take a look at how this pollutant will cause health and economic damage.
この汚染物質が健康と経済にどのような被害をもたらすかを見てみましょう。
Of course, our current industry or environmental protection policies will cause some pollution sources
もちろん、現在の産業や環境保護政策は何らかの汚染源を引き起こすでしょう。
Then what happens after these pollution sources are discharged?
では、これらの汚染源が排出された後はどうなるのでしょうか？
After conversion, it will form the surrounding environment concentration just mentioned
変換後は、先ほど述べた周囲環境濃度となります。
Then this week, if the environmental concentration is going to affect our health
それでは今週、環境濃度が私たちの健康に影響を与えるかどうか
we must be able to say
私たちは言うことができるはずです
This creates our external concentration
これにより外部への集中が生まれます
we sucked in
私たちは吸い込まれた
The nose will inhale in order to affect our health
鼻は息を吸い込むことで私たちの健康に影響を与えます
Can't suck in
吸い込めない
won't come in
入ってこない
All will not affect our health
すべては私たちの健康に影響を与えません
So the most important thing is actually the body's external concentration
つまり、最も重要なことは実際には体の外部への集中力です
The EPA is testing
EPAがテスト中
In fact, it is the surrounding concentration of pollutants
実際には、それは周囲の汚染物質の濃度です
It's actually like I just mentioned
実はさっき言ったようなんです
It is not equal to the present concentration outside the human body
現在の人体外の濃度とは異なります
Extrinsic concentration of the human body
人体の本質的な集中力
In fact, this is not easy to measure
実際、これを測定するのは簡単ではありません
I don't know if you have ever visited the EPA's test war
あなたがEPAのテスト戦争を訪れたことがあるかどうかは知りません
About six or seven pollutants
6～7種類の汚染物質について
It needs to fill a small room with a size of seven to ten pings
7～10坪の小さな部屋を満たす必要がある
Different instruments and some cylinders
さまざまな器具といくつかのシリンダー
OK
OK
so you can imagine
想像できるように
You have to measure the front of your nose
鼻の前を測らなければなりません
you can't take an instrument
楽器を持ち込むことはできません
Hold a cylinder and keep going
シリンダーを持って進み続けます
right
右
So to measure this dangerous concentration
この危険な濃度を測定するには
It's not easy
簡単ではない
So it needs a portable observation instrument
そのため、持ち運び可能な観測機器が必要です
to measure
測定する
Then this portable observation instrument
そこでこの携帯型観測装置
good enough
十分です
for scientific purposes
科学的目的のため
OK
OK
So this is what we were doing before
これが私たちが以前にやっていたことでした
When this external dangerous concentration
この外部からの危険な集中が起こると、
a big challenge
大きな挑戦
then one more word
それからもう一言
we should mention that
それについて言及する必要があります
In fact, the dangerous concentration of the human body
実は人体の危険な濃度は
because we are close
私たちは近いから
including when we cook
料理するときも含めて
including when we lose
負けた時も含めて
including before we ride a motorcycle
バイクに乗る前も含めて
When a car emits black smoke
車から黒煙が出るとき
what we inhaled
私たちが吸い込んだもの
Actually a cutting-edge concentration
実は最先端の集中力
What about the tip concentration?
先端の濃度はどうでしょうか？
EPA is undetectable
EPAは検出されない
Because it's gone in an instant
一瞬でなくなるから
OK
OK
Therefore, the freshness measured by the concentration of Jannain
したがって、鮮度はジャナインの濃度で測ります。
What about the concentration of the fresh pollutants it emits?
そこから排出される新たな汚染物質の濃度はどうなるのでしょうか？
or this ingredient
またはこの成分
OK
OK
It is also different from the evenly mixed composition measured by the Environmental Protection Agency.
環境保護庁が測定した均一に混合された組成とも異なります。
OK because it's been hours
OK、もう何時間も経ったから
OK
OK
So the composition is different and the concentration is not the same
つまり組成が異なり、濃度も同じではありません
so it actually
それで実際には
If we use the concentration of the surrounding environment to represent the concentration we don't like
嫌いな濃度を周囲環境の濃度で表すと
Many things behind are misleading
背後にある多くのものが誤解を招く
including it would be misleading
それを含めると誤解を招きます
our this
私たちのこれ
how to measure us
私たちをどう測るか
The effect of actual damage to health
実際の健康被害の影響
Health Effect OK
健康影響OK
health damage factor
健康被害要因
this is misleading
これは誤解を招きます
that especially in
それは特に
With so many sources of pollution in this community in Taiwan
台湾のこの地域には汚染源が非常に多いため、
it may
かもしれない
more misleading
もっと誤解を招く
Let's take a look at
見てみましょう
In fact, even in Europe and the United States
実は欧米でも
Europe and the United States do not have such complex community pollution sources as ours
ヨーロッパと米国には、我が国のような複雑な地域汚染源はありません。
Europe and the United States are relatively simple
ヨーロッパとアメリカは比較的単純です
Europe and the United States often say that
欧米ではよくこう言われます。
whatever it is
それが何であれ
Probably the concentration of PM2.5 in my backyard
おそらく裏庭のPM2.5濃度
OK, if their family didn't mention some other sources of pollution
OK、家族が他の汚染源について言及していなければ
Like this fast frying and so on
こんな早揚げとか
probably that's about it
おそらくそれくらいです
but even so
しかしそれでも
let's take a look
見てみましょう
If the ambient concentration is used to represent the acceptable concentration
許容濃度を表すために周囲濃度が使用される場合
We underestimate the health damage of pollutants
私たちは汚染物質による健康被害を過小評価しています
This is a well-known one or two studies in the United States
これは米国で 1 つか 2 つの有名な研究です。
This is American Cancer Research
これがアメリカのがん研究です
there is a famous author
有名な作家がいます
He is using urban monitoring stations to represent the concentration of people in the whole city
彼は都市の監視ステーションを使用して、都市全体の人々の集中を表現しています。
The result he got was
彼が得た結果は、
10 wick per rise
立ち上がりごとに10本の芯
PM2.5 per cubic meter
PM2.5/立方メートル
His overall death rate will increase by 6%
彼の全体的な死亡率は6%増加します
OK up 6%
OK 6%アップ
that same one
それと同じもの
population in the same cancer cohort
同じがんコホート内の集団
this study
この研究
But different researchers
しかし、研究者は異なります
He used a nearby monitoring station
彼は近くの監視ステーションを使用しました
and he took into account different traffic flows
そして彼はさまざまな交通の流れを考慮に入れました
That is, different areas have different traffic flows.
つまり、エリアが異なれば交通の流れも異なります。
Use such a more detailed method to estimate the population of the people
このようなより詳細な方法を使用して人口を推定する
exposure concentration
暴露濃度
what did he get
彼は何を手に入れましたか
Every rise of 10 victoria meters
ビクトリアメートルが10メートル上がるごとに
The overall death rate will increase by 17%
全体的な死亡率は17%増加する
That is 3 times higher
それは3倍高いです
This is 3 times higher
これは3倍高いです
It is because his exposure concentration estimation is more accurate
それは、彼の暴露濃度推定の方が正確だからです。
What about this estimate?
この見積もりはどうでしょうか？
Also with the other one in Europe is also using
また、他のヨーロッパでも使用されています
It is also a more accurate way of land return
これは土地返還のより正確な方法でもあります
To estimate the concentration of exposure
暴露濃度を推定するには
The estimated 13% is relatively close
推定 13% は比較的近い値です
OK
OK
So scientifically speaking
つまり科学的に言えば
How can we get more accurate
より正確にするにはどうすればよいですか
Exposure concentration is a very, very important issue
暴露濃度は非常に重要な問題です
Because science is basically about finding the truth.
なぜなら、科学とは基本的に真実を見つけることだからです。
We have the closest true exposure concentration value
最も近い真の暴露濃度値が得られます
We can compare to estimate
見積もり比較できる
More accurate this P2.5
この P2.5 の方が正確です
How does it harm your health?
健康にどのような悪影響を及ぼしますか?
At present, these large-scale studies in Europe and the United States
現在、ヨーロッパとアメリカではこれらの大規模な研究が行われています。
Basically they're talking about long-term exposure to pollutants
基本的に彼らは汚染物質への長期曝露について話している
long-term bleeding
長期にわたる出血
Damage factor for long-term chronic health damage to health
長期にわたる慢性的な健康被害のダメージ要因
for acute injuries
急性の怪我の場合
including what we just mentioned
先ほど述べたことも含めて
Emissions from cars and locomotives in front
前方の車両や機関車からの排気ガス
or when we cook
または料理をするとき
Exposure to higher concentrations
高濃度への曝露
Such an exposure when I like barbecue on Mid-Autumn Festival
中秋節のバーベキューが好きならこんな露出も
What is the harm to our own health?
私たち自身の健康に害を及ぼすものは何ですか
Now, very little is known
今ではほとんど知られていない
because of technical limitations
技術的な制限のため
Fortunately, it is also because in recent years
幸いなことに、それは近年のことでもあります
Especially the technical limitations in the past two years
特に過去 2 年間の技術的な限界
Our future is likely to be in this area
私たちの未来はおそらくこの領域にあります
in the assessment of acute health effects
急性健康影響の評価において
can make better progress
より良い進歩を遂げることができる
This is also the direction our research team wants to work on in the future
これは私たちの研究チームが将来的に取り組みたい方向でもあります
ok let's see
わかりました、見てみましょう
We have been talking about the prevention and treatment of kidney stasis
腎うっ滞の予防と治療についてお話してきました。
So in the middle of something like this
それで、こんなことの途中で
What in this process
このプロセスで何が行われるか
is the point of entry where we can intervene policy
私たちが政策に介入できる入り口です
If we have better industrial and environmental protection policies
より良い産業および環境保護政策があれば
In terms of environmental governance
環境ガバナンスの観点から
We will reduce a lot of pollution sources
私たちは多くの汚染源を削減します
that's the best, right?
それが最高ですよね？
Prevention of Kidney Stasis Treatment
腎うっ滞の予防治療
Or you discharge pollutants
あるいは汚染物質を排出する
But I figured out how to prevent pollution from it
しかし、私はそれによる汚染を防ぐ方法を見つけました
catch you
あなたを捕まえて
OK this is OK
OK、これはOKです
But there is no 100% pollution in the world
しかし、世界に100%の汚染は存在しません
100% pollution control equipment that can be caught
100％捕獲可能な公害防止装置
once it's discharged
排出されたら
The next one that can protect our health
私たちの健康を守る次のもの
That is, how do we think of ways to block this exposure channel?
つまり、この暴露経路をブロックする方法をどのように考えるかということです。
so even in the air
だから空中でも
But we won't be exposed to this
しかし、私たちはこれにさらされることはありません
then we'll be safe
そうすれば私たちは安全です
ok this is next
はい、次はこれです
So these three points
ということでこの３点
Basically, policy can intervene
基本的には政策が介入できる
Points to reduce health risks
健康リスクを軽減するためのポイント
Then our scientific problem is actually
それでは、私たちの科学的問題は実際には
We want to know what the actual risk concentration of the people is
人々の実際のリスク集中がどの程度なのかを知りたい
What kind of impact factor does that have?
それはどのようなインパクトファクターを持っていますか？
Are there potential sources of neglected pollutants?
放置されている汚染物質の潜在的な発生源はありますか?
we forget we ignore
私たちは忘れます、無視します
Then there is how we can block this dangerous path
では、どうすればこの危険な道をブロックできるのかということです
So can protect our health
それで私たちの健康を守ることができます
This is what we did in Taiwan
これは台湾でやったことです
This is a 400-meter community
ここは400メートルの集落です
Then we take the instrument
それから楽器を手に取ります
Walk along this street for about an hour and a half
この通りを1時間半ほど歩きます
You can see that its concentration is three times different
濃度が3倍違うのがわかります
Concentrations can be three times higher in some places with polluting source community sources
地域社会の汚染源がある場所では、濃度が 3 倍高くなる可能性があります
This is what we call community pollution
これがいわゆる地域社会汚染です
The impact of community emission sources on the concentration of human hazards
人的危険の集中に対するコミュニティ排出源の影響
It will also have an impact on the air quality of our communities
私たちのコミュニティの大気質にも影響を与えるでしょう
So in Asia
それでアジアでは
In fact, Europe and the United States are really different
実はヨーロッパとアメリカは全然違うんです
We are not only subject to
実際、私たちが影響を受けるのはそれだけではありません。
Influence of surrounding environment concentration
周囲環境濃度の影響
OK Our Personal Concentration
OK 私たちの個人的な集中
environment
環境
Coupled with these increases in community emission sources
これらのコミュニティ排出源の増加と相まって
coupled with our individual behavior
私たち個人の行動と結びついて
including if you are going to smoke
喫煙する場合も含めて
OK or cooking or doing any activity
OK、料理をするか何かのアクティビティをするか
This is generated by pumping this self
これはこの自己をポンピングすることによって生成されます
So what is the concentration of each of us?
では、私たち一人一人の集中力はどれくらいでしょうか？
In fact, it is a combination of these three
実はこの３つを組み合わせたものなのですが、
OK put together
OK、まとめて
so which one is more
それでどっちが多いですか
that is, not everyone
つまり全員ではない
what about our team
私たちのチームはどうですか
It's not always a survey
必ずしも調査というわけではありません
as if we researched this
あたかも私たちがこれを調べたかのように
How high are you this time, how low will you be next time
今回はどれくらい高くなりますか、次回はどれくらい低くなりますか
it's over
終わりました
not like this
こんなんじゃない
we're talking about forever
私たちは永遠について話しています
What is the factor
その要因は何ですか
will affect the concentration of the waterfall
滝の濃度に影響します
Then what is the emission of this waterfall?
では、この滝の放出量は何でしょうか?
What is the increase in emissions
排出量の増加は何ですか
What is the emission factor
排出係数とは何ですか
After having these
これらを持った後、
In order to draw all these data together
これらすべてのデータを統合するには
Then on the one hand, it is possible to estimate more precisely
そうすれば、一方では、より正確に推定することが可能になります
Our Risk Concentration
当社のリスク集中
So we can calculate
それで計算できます
to study our health damage coefficient
私たちの健康被害係数を調べるため
it's a purpose
それは目的です
one more word
もう一言
More importantly, we can also put
さらに重要なことは、次のようにすることもできます。
this factor of this risk
このリスクのこの要因
add up to one of us
合計すると私たちの一人になります
what we call catastrophe mode
私たちがカタストロフィモードと呼ぶもの
OK
OK
So in the future, this waterfall mode
したがって、将来的には、このウォーターフォールモードは
we can use
私たちは使うことができます
Do a lot of other science above this discussion
この議論以外にも他の多くの科学を行ってください
ok let's see
わかりました、見てみましょう
We are curious in this land
私たちはこの土地に興味がある
Are we usually in the community?
私たちは普段コミュニティにいますか？
how to go around
どうやって回るか
OK
OK
Let me show you here
ここでお見せしましょう
This is what we worked hard for
これが私たちが一生懸命頑張ってきたことです
The assistant and the student
アシスタントと生徒
It's really just a push cart
本当にただの手押し車です
He has a very precise instrument on it.
彼は非常に精密な器具を持っています。
OK detour along the community
集落沿いに寄り道OK
and he can't go too fast
そして彼はあまり速く走れない
OK he has to walk slowly
OK、彼はゆっくり歩かなければなりません
So in very hot conditions
したがって、非常に暑い状況では
if you see this girl
この女の子を見たら
Still wearing this visor hat
まだこのバイザーハットをかぶっています
If this girl is on the side of the road
もしこの女の子が道端にいたら
We also need to register some, including cars and motorcycles passing by the roadside
道路脇を通過する車やバイクなども登録する必要があります。
He has to count, he has to do a lot of record work
彼は数えなければならず、多くの記録作業をしなければならない
Only by recording it like this can we know
こうやって記録することでしか分からない
Which factors will emit how much pollution increase
どの要因が排出し、どれだけ汚染が増加するか
Some passers-by will also be curious
通行人も興味津々の人もいるでしょう
so what are we doing
それで私たちは何をしているのですか
And then we'll all tell him we're measuring the air quality
それからみんなで空気の質を測定していることを彼に伝えましょう
Then he said good very good
それから彼は「良かった、とても良かった」と言った
We really need you to test this air quality
この空気の質をぜひテストしてもらいたいのです
like this this car goes by
このようにしてこの車が通ります
This is actually when ordinary people are waiting for the red jade lantern.
実はこの時期、ほとんどの人が赤い翡翠の提灯を待っているのです。
will stay at this intersection
この交差点に留まります
OK this is all in the alley
OK、ここはすべて路地の中にあります
we are simulating words
私たちは言葉をシミュレートしています
In fact, we also saw old people who were about our height
実際、私たちと同じくらいの身長の老人も見かけました。
He rides this car, do you have electric cars?
彼はこの車に乗っていますが、電気自動車はありますか?
when he is walking or the baby is in the stroller
赤ちゃんが歩いているとき、または赤ちゃんがベビーカーに乗っているとき
are also so high
もとても高いです
So we are also simulating the actual
そこで実際のシミュレーションも行っています
when people actually do these everyday things
人々がこれらの日常的なことを実際に行っているとき
The exposure concentration of
暴露濃度は、
Then we also explore the factor behind him
次に、彼の背後にある要因も探ります
This is a video of our live
これは私たちのライブのビデオです
In fact, our personal PM2.5 concentration
実際、私たちの個人的な PM2.5 濃度は
technology over the years
長年にわたるテクノロジー
Great progress has been made in the analysis of this observation technique
この観測技術の解析は大きく進歩しました
We're going to have a pump before new year's
新年前にポンプを用意する予定です
Connect a sampling head to pump air
サンプリングヘッドを空気ポンプに接続します
So we're going to pump air with a filter paper in it
濾紙を入れて空気を送り込みます
So you can accumulate PM2.5
PM2.5が蓄積しやすいので
Its advantage is that this filter paper can also be used for chemical analysis later
その利点は、この濾紙を後で化学分析にも使用できることです。
will analyze some ingredients that are harmful to health
健康に有害な成分を分析します
its downside is
その欠点は
I actually took this myself
実はこれ自分で撮ったんです
This set is about 2.5 kg
このセットは約2.5kgです
You will think that this 2.5 kg is nothing
この2.5kgなんて何でもないと思うでしょう
right
右
It also vibrates a little bit
振動も少しあります
You'll feel like the first five minutes are nothing
最初の5分間は何でもないように感じるでしょう
You'll know after you vibrate it for half an hour
30分振動させればわかります
It vibrated to the point where I couldn't do anything else that day
その日は何もできなくなるほど震えた
i can only watch tv
テレビしか見られない
you can't think
あなたには考えられない
Because it just doesn't work and keeps vibrating inside
機能せず、内部で振動し続けるため
and it's going to be a little bit noisy
そして少し騒がしくなるでしょう
that noise too
あの騒音も
The first five minutes you thought it was okay
最初の5分は関係ないと思った
then wait until half an hour
それから30分まで待ちます
Then I started to feel unbearable
それから私は耐えられないと感じ始めました
So we're also grateful for the years
だから私たちも何年にもわたって感謝しています
The assistants and volunteers who helped us bring these observation instruments
観測機器の搬入に協力してくれたアシスタントやボランティアの皆さん
Then they have to take 4 hours to 24 hours
その場合は 4 時間から 24 時間かかります
OK take so long before we can collect enough
十分な量を集めるまでに時間がかかります
to do chemical analysis
化学分析をする
OK this was 20 years ago
OK、これは20年前のことです
Then I came to Academia Sinica
それから中央研究院に来ました
So I am very grateful that Academia Sinica has money to support
したがって、中央研究院が資金を提供してくれることに非常に感謝しています。
We bought a western belt for this
このためにウエスタンベルトを購入しました
The particle regime instrument
粒子レジーム装置
It is possible to measure this particle size distribution
この粒度分布の測定が可能です
Also includes PN2.5
PN2.5も含む
This is about two to three kilograms
これで２～３キロくらいです
OK but because it's too expensive
いいけど高すぎるから
So we can only sell these two sets
なのでこの2セットしか販売できません
And it was brought by my assistant
アシスタントさんが持ってきてくれました
We dare not bring volunteers
あえてボランティアを連れてこない
Because if it hits
当たったら
We're about to pass out
気絶しそう
OK, then we can collect one piece of data per minute
OK、それでは 1 分あたり 1 つのデータを収集できます
Now, we are cooperating with the teachers of the information center
現在、情報センターの先生方にご協力いただいております。
So now it has developed like this
それで今はこんな展開になりました
Simple, this one is only 200 grams
シンプルに、これはたったの200グラムです
it is paired with a
とペアになっています
mobile power bank
モバイルパワーバンク
Then it can also be equipped with temperature and humidity inside
その後、内部の温度と湿度を装備することもできます
Then this GPS and Wi-Fi, it can transmit wirelessly
この GPS と Wi-Fi は、無線で送信できます
There is also an SD card, which can save its data
データを保存できるSDカードもあります
There can be a data every 15 seconds
15 秒ごとにデータが存在する可能性があります
So if the instrument of research like now
だから今のような研究手段なら
We can study more later
後でもっと勉強できます
The client's liability, and the acute liability
顧客の責任と重大な責任
relationship with health effects
健康影響との関係
This is what we designed this year
今年はこんなデザインにしました
we started early
私たちは早く始めました
we were in 1999
私たちは1999年にいた
We are actually in six communities in the north, central and south
私たちは実際、北部、中部、南部の 6 つのコミュニティに所属しています。
to recruit volunteers
ボランティアを募集する
Thank you to the five or sixty volunteers
5、60人のボランティアの皆さん、ありがとうございました
Willing to wear a sampler like this
このようなサンプラーを着用したい
Wear it 24 hours a day
24時間着用してください
when they wear
彼らが着るとき
They also help us fill out questionnaires
彼らはアンケートへの記入も手伝ってくれます
He just told us every 30 minutes
彼は30分ごとに私たちに言いました
Was he indoors or outdoors at that time?
その時彼は屋内にいましたか、それとも屋外にいましたか?
Is there any source of pollution near him?
彼の近くに汚染源はありますか
including someone smoking
喫煙している人も含めて
There is this car exhaust
この車の排気ガスがあります
There is this family setting off firecrackers
爆竹を鳴らしている家族がいます
what are these details
これらの詳細は何ですか
then what is he doing
それで彼は何をしているのですか
he is riding a motorcycle
彼はオートバイに乗っています
still here
まだここ
do any of this activity
このアクティビティのいずれかを行う
ok watching tv and so on
はい、テレビなどを見ています
That's because we need this schedule of his activities
それは彼の活動スケジュールが必要だからです
to be able to analyze
分析できるようになる
Why on earth do some people have high concentration
一体なぜ一部の人は集中力が高いのでしょうか
Some people have lower concentrations
集中力が低い人もいます
Because we can only accumulate one data in 24 hours
24時間に1つのデータしか蓄積できないので
ok at that time
わかりました、その時は
What about this research?
この研究についてはどうですか？
actually very very important
実はとてもとても重要
This is the first in Taiwan
台湾では初めてです
This is actually in the community
これは実際にコミュニティ内にあります
See this study on particulate exposure
微粒子曝露に関するこの研究を参照
Then he is targeting PM10
そして彼はPM10をターゲットにしている
At that time, there was no PM2.5
当時はPM2.5なんてなかった
What about this study?
この研究はどうですか？
In fact, this electric
実はこの電気、
The basis of my future research
私の将来の研究の基礎
he pointed out two
彼は二つ指摘した
In fact, in European and American studies
実際、欧米の研究では
rarely pointed out
稀に指摘される
First
初め
Research tells us that indoor air quality
研究によると、室内の空気の質は
Concentrations of pollutants are higher indoors than outdoors
汚染物質の濃度は屋外より屋内の方が高い
Because Europe and the United States don’t care if they have cats and dogs at home
ヨーロッパとアメリカは家に犬や猫がいても気にしないから
Because of the carpet or something
カーペットか何かのせいで
Although they are not decorated with high heat, quick fry or burn incense
高温で焼くわけではありませんが、さっと炒めたり、お香を焚いたりしてください。
But their indoor concentration is really relatively high
しかし、彼らの屋内集中力は実際には比較的高いです
Indoor is higher than outdoor
屋内は屋外より高い
we are the opposite
私たちは反対です
We are higher outdoor than indoor
屋内よりも屋外の方が高い
At first, I felt a little bit unconvinced.
最初は少し納得いかない気持ちもありました。
I later discussed with other researchers in public health
その後、公衆衛生分野の他の研究者たちと議論しました。
They said that the few cases they tested were actually like this
彼らは、彼らがテストしたいくつかのケースは実際に次のようなものだったと言った
what does that mean
どういう意味ですか
This means that we are actually too dirty outside.
これは、実際には外があまりにも汚れていることを意味します
OK
OK
real
本物
OK because we really have a lot of community pollution sources outdoors
屋外には地域社会の汚染源が実際にたくさんあるからです
This is why it continued to be a source of community pollution.
これが、地域社会の汚染源であり続けた理由です。
Because it is from the outdoors of the community
コミュニティの屋外からですので
it passes
それは通ります
because you don't care how it closes the window
窓をどのように閉めるかは気にしないからです
it just has air exchange
空気の入れ替えがあるだけです
it comes from outside to inside
それは外側から内側へやってくる
OK will affect the indoor air quality
OK は室内の空気の質に影響を与えます
very different
とても違う
Second point
2点目
Actually doing this abroad
海外では実際にやってる
powerless personal exposure
無力な個人暴露
personal exposure
個人曝顯
maybe make it out
もしかしたらうまくいくかもしれない
main conclusion
最主要的結論
It may be that people who smoke have a higher concentration
タバコを吸う人の方が集中力が高いのかもしれない
probably their most important one
おそらく彼らにとって最も重要なもの
The exposure factor is this
露出係数はこちら
but we make it
しかし、私たちはそれをやり遂げます
Like the 50 or so people I recruited
私が採用した50人ほどの人たちと同じように
Actually they don't smoke
実は彼らはタバコを吸いません
the non-smoker
非喫煙者
But they have different
しかし、彼らは違います
This exposed behavior
この暴露行為
will make their concentration
彼らの集中力を高めます
Individual concentration is higher than others
個人の集中力が他の人よりも高い
the most obvious
最も明らかな
What about this exposed behavior?
この暴露された行動についてはどうですか？
the first motorcycle
最初のバイク
biker outside
外のバイカー
He's just taller than a guy who doesn't ride a bike
彼は自転車に乗らない人よりも背が高いだけだ
he average
彼は平均的です
his concentration words
彼の集中力の言葉
High exposure concentration of 20 gram
20グラムの高濃度暴露
per cubic meter
立方メートルあたり
In addition, people who are slightly defeated are also
また、ちょっと負け気味の人も
and the ones in the kitchen
そしてキッチンにあるもの
stay in the kitchen
キッチンに残る
not my own cooking
自分の料理ではない
Because we all asked him about this activity
みんなでこの活動について彼に聞いたので、
it's him in the kitchen
キッチンにいるのは彼です
with his wife or his mother
彼の妻または母親と一緒に
this chat
このチャット
His negative risk concentration will be high
彼のネガティブなリスク集中は高くなるだろう
And these households actually have range hoods for driving
そして、これらの家庭には実際に運転用のレンジフードがあります
ok, but his negative risk concentration will still be relatively high
わかりましたが、彼のマイナスのリスク集中は依然として比較的高いでしょう
there is another
もう一つの...がある
It is time to pass the small community factory
小さな町工場を通過する時間です
ok because we have too many Taiwan
台湾には多すぎるから大丈夫
weird little factory
奇妙な小さな工場
Our so-called small factories are actually a lot of traffickers
私たちのいわゆる小さな工場には、実際には人身売買業者がたくさんいます
Like this motorcycle repair shop, small carpenter, etc.
このバイク修理工場や小さな大工さんなど。
The shop and business of metal, etc. are all
金属などのショップやビジネスは全て
ok after these
OK、この後
he didn't go in he just passed by
彼は中には入らなかった、ただ通り過ぎただけだ
he will be taller
彼はもっと背が高くなります
ok, so these, these, and this information
さて、これら、これら、そしてこの情報
that's why we will
だからこそ私たちはそうするのです
Research this community pollution source
このコミュニティの汚染源を調査する
ok now a quick word on this
さて、これについて簡単に言っておきます
Everyone in Asia knows this
アジア人なら誰でも知ってる
we are all around
私たちは周りにいます
we because we like to have
私たちはそれが好きだから
good life function
良好な生活機能
Our family can eat a lot of this car
私たち家族はこの車をたくさん食べることができます
Gongmiao, this hair salon
公廟（ゴンミャオ）の美容院です。
wait for the night market
ナイトマーケットを待ちます
ok
Ok
Then these words will emit these pn2.5
次に、これらの単語はこれらの pn2.5 を出力します。
some are direct emissions
一部は直接排出です
It also does not require secondary pollution
二次汚染も必要ありません
It emits a lot of direct emissions
直接排出量が多い
Then this is our community
それでは、ここが私たちのコミュニティです
Actually use the more expensive one
実際には高価なものを使用してください
instrument to do
やるべき楽器
Gongmiao next to the catering industry
外食産業の隣にある公廟
beside
それ以外
Most people wait for the work toilet to see
ほとんどの人は職場のトイレを待っています
After all, these will cause
結局のところ、これらは原因になります
How much concentration increments do we
どれくらい集中力が上がるのか
then we also
それなら私たちも
This is one of the materials
これも素材の一つです
this is to see this
これはこれを見るためです
This filter distributes
このフィルターは、
That's 0.1 microns and all the way up to 100
それは 0.1 ミクロンから 100 までです
so we can see
それで私たちは見ることができます
The words behind are background points
後ろの言葉は背景ポイントです
very light color
とても明るい色
The word before that is the catering industry
その前の言葉はケータリング業界です
So we can know the words of the restaurant industry
飲食業界の言葉を知ることができるように
it is
それはです
Possibly larger filters
おそらくより大きなフィルター
or emit into very, very small filters
または、非常に非常に小さなフィルターに放射します
The words of Gongmiao
公廟の言葉
Almost the emissions are exactly what we breathe
ほとんどの排気ガスは私たちが呼吸するものとまったく同じです
It is like this below pn2.5
pn2.5以下はこんな感じ
this range
この範囲
The emission from the factory site is relatively large.
工場敷地からの排出量は比較的多い。
filter range
フィルター範囲
From these we can see that comparing
これらから、比較すると次のことがわかります。
Emission sources in this different community
この異なるコミュニティの排出源
The vili that was released was actually
放出されたビリは実際には
Different circumstances
さまざまな状況
In addition, we can also use this statistical method
さらに、この統計的手法を使用することもできます。
How to analyze data
データを分析する方法
These catering industry with oily fumes
油煙が発生するケータリング業界
Temple construction site etc.
寺院の建設現場など
All for our PN2.5
すべてはPN2.5のために
Wait, there is this obvious contribution
待ってください、この明らかな貢献があります
Then everyone probably in the past five years or
そうすると、おそらく誰もが過去 5 年間か、
Only noticed in the past week or two
ここ1～2週間で気づいた
This temple minus this thing
この寺院からこれを除いたもの
In fact, because I made this incense-related
実はこれお香関連で作ったものなので
This study has been done for more than ten years
この研究は10年以上行われています
So I actually spent the past few years in this
それで私は実際に過去数年間をこれに費やしました
do these studies
これらの研究をする
I was also invited to this
私もこれに誘われました
Like last year, there were two chances to go to Central
昨年同様、セントラル行きのチャンスは2回あった
This is the local religious group
これは地元の宗教団体です
They are spontaneous to promote
彼らは自発的に宣伝する
Events at Eco-friendly Temples
環境に配慮した寺院のイベント
Really try to use self-management as much as possible
できる限り自己管理を心がけましょう
Minimize
最小化する
So we've actually seen over the years
私たちは何年にもわたって実際に見てきました
They're really pushing the same box
彼らは本当に同じ箱を押している
When I used to do
以前やっていたとき
In fact, some are like three incense sticks or more
実際には、お線香が 3 本以上あるものもあります。
OK
OK
So they really have this
それで彼らは本当にこれを持っています
tried my best
最善を尽くしました
Of course the EPA is also kind
もちろんEPAも親切です
Because it is true that when you burn incense and fail
お香を焚いて失敗するのは本当だから
you hold it in front of your nose
あなたはそれを鼻の前に持ちます
So you are this about your health
つまり、あなたは自分の健康についてこれを考えています
Your invisibility is very high
あなたの不可視性は非常に高いです
OK is bad for your health
OKは健康に悪い
so good intentions on both sides
双方とも非常に善意がある
But in the end this
でも結局これ
There may be some misunderstandings in the middle
途中で誤解があるかもしれません
OK
OK
Well, I've been talking to this environmental group over the years
私はこの環境保護団体と何年にもわたって話し合ってきました
or a religious group
または宗教団体
when this interaction
このやり取りのとき
Learned a lot from them
彼らから多くのことを学びました
the first they also say
最初に彼らはこうも言います
This proverb says
このことわざはこう言っています
Burning incense from fortune telling
占いでお香を焚く
OK, why is it that the one who pays burns incense?
では、なぜお金を払う人がお香を焚くのでしょうか？
Because the incense used to be very expensive
お香は昔はとても高価だったので
They are all made with very precious traditional Chinese medicine.
これらはすべて、非常に貴重な伝統的な漢方薬で作られています。
So it burns out very
だからとても燃え尽きるんです
This is very fragrant and comfortable
これはとても香りが良くて心地よいです
Not now, now there are a lot of annual plans to study medicine
今ではなく、今では医学を勉強するための年間計画がたくさんあります
In fact, if it burns out, it is very likely that there will be a lot of sperm and eggs
実際、燃え尽きると大量の精子と卵子が存在する可能性が非常に高い
I myself have done research on the direction of cancer treatment, and analyzed it
私自身、がん治療の方向性について研究し、分析してきました。
Then other scholars have also made it, and you have burned heavy metals
それから他の学者もそれを作りました、そしてあなたは重金属を燃やしました
This is all published in the literature
これはすべて文献に掲載されています
So the fragrance of the past is different from the fragrance of the present
だから昔の香りと今の香りは違うんだよ
In addition, the refinement of the past is not the same as the refinement of the present.
さらに、過去の洗練は現在の洗練と同じではありません。
The one in the middle of the previous exquisiteness is Xibo
前回の絶妙さの真ん中にあるのはXiboです
Now the middle is plastic, what will the plastic burn out
今は真ん中がプラスチックになっていますが、プラスチックは燃え尽きるのでしょうか？
We all know, waist type
誰もが知っているウエストタイプ
So this is where there are many differences between the past and the present
ここが過去と現在で多くの違いがあるところです
But these religious groups are actually trying to do
しかし、これらの宗教団体が実際にやろうとしているのは、
These are the words of the local faith center
これは地元の信仰センターの言葉です
We also selected these two recent reports
これら 2 つの最近のレポートも選択しました
In fact, it also shows that these religious groups
実際、これらの宗教団体が
They are actually very considerate of everyone.
実際、彼らは誰に対してもとても思いやりがあります。
For example, when passing the examinee's place, he is forbidden to become
たとえば、受験者の場所を通過するときに、次のことは禁止されています。
Bubble and loudspeaker while playing
再生中のバブルとスピーカー
let the grill suffer
グリルを苦しめましょう
Or when Mazu is oily
または媽祖が油っぽいとき
Also do not let the side soak along the way
側面も途中で浸さないようにしてください
They are also promoting environmental protection
環境保護も推進している
concept of health
健康の概念
I have been from 1999 to now
私は1999年から現在まで
I did a series of
一連のことをしました
There are experiments related to burning incense
お香を焚く実験もある
including watching in the lab
研究室での観察も含めて
different edema
異なる浮腫
It's burned out PN2.5
燃え尽きました PN2.5
Shout out to the Fragrance Hall
フレグランスホールに声をかけてください
Then we are in this
それでは、私たちはこの中にいます
Xiangke at home
自宅にいる香科
defeat every day or
毎日負けるか、
go to temple every month
毎月お寺に行く
or this
またはこれ
When talking about Mazu looking in the mirror
鏡を見ながら媽祖のことを話しているとき
what are they
彼らは何ですか
how much exposure
どのくらいの露出
What else is this impact factor
このインパクトファクターは他に何ですか
OK
OK
then i emphasize
それから私は強調します
have always been
いつもそうだった
controllable factors
制御可能な要素
what factor
どのような要因があるのか
can help him reduce his risk concentration
彼のリスク集中を軽減するのに役立つ可能性がある
I've been telling this student
私はこの生徒にこう言いました。
or when people communicate
あるいは人々がコミュニケーションをとるとき
speaking
話し中
our purpose
私たちの目的
I hope to say how to go
行き方を言いたいと思います
keep the tradition
伝統を守る
Folk while reducing health risks
健康リスクを軽減しながらフォークをする
In fact, that's what I told the gods
実は神様にそう言ったんです
when i go to the temple to do it
お寺に行ってそれをするとき
I must first worship the gods
まず神々を崇拝しなければなりません
And speak to him very reverently
そしてとてもうやうやしく彼に話しかけてください
I'm not trying to change folklore beliefs
私は民間伝承の信念を変えようとしているわけではありません
I hope everyone engages in the same folk beliefs when
誰もが同じ民間信仰に参加することを願っています
How to reduce the risk to your health
健康へのリスクを軽減する方法
So most of the gods agree that I am in the temple
だからほとんどの神々は私が神殿にいることに同意する
Do observations like this
このような観察をしてください
only one did not agree
一人だけが同意しませんでした
I asked three times and he still didn't agree
3回尋ねましたが、彼はまだ同意しませんでした
I just thank him
私は彼にただ感謝しています
I'm leaving
私は行きます
that's all
それで全部です
so we just respect
だから私たちはただ尊敬するだけです
events like temples
お寺などのイベント
So like I would suggest
だから私が提案するように
When everyone is burning incense
みんなでお香を焚いているとき
The first must be ventilated
最初は換気する必要があります
of course we all know
もちろん私たちは皆知っています
Telescope with censer
香炉付き望遠鏡
will also affect the concentration of the waterfall
滝の濃度にも影響します
But ventilation is the most important
でも換気が一番大事
It doesn't matter if you're close to him as long as it's ventilated
換気されていれば近くにいても問題ありません
The concentration of ventilation can be as bad as
換気の集中は次のように悪化する可能性があります。
seven or eight times more
七八倍以上
Xiangzhi tree, Xianglulu, etc. used in temples
寺院で使用される香芝木、香ルルなど
Or when Dajia Matsu circled in
あるいは、ダジア・マツがサークルインしたとき
For everyone, it is better to take this kind of big bus.
皆さんもこのような大型バスに乗った方が良いでしょう。
Otherwise, you will directly ride a motorcycle and be directly exposed to more serious
そうしないと、オートバイに直接乗って、より深刻な事態に直接さらされることになります。
These are controllable factors
これらは制御可能な要素です
In addition, we also want to talk about this walking and jumping night market
さらに、この歩いてジャンプする夜市についても話したいと思います
This is actually my favorite night market.
実はここが私の一番好きな夜市なんです。
This night market is not the night market on the promotional materials
この夜市は宣伝物にある夜市ではありません
it's different
違います
Another word is because our data is made with sensors
別の言葉で言えば、私たちのデータはセンサーで作られているからです
So it hasn't been corrected by this science
つまりこの科学では修正されていない
It's just that there is a trend now that I can show it to everyone
ただ今トレンドがあるので皆さんにお見せできます
If we're here, we're entering a palace
私たちがここにいるなら、私たちは宮殿に入っていることになる
Its concentration will increase a lot
集中力がかなり高まります
then we passed a lot of kebab places
それから私たちはたくさんのケバブの店を通り過ぎました
Yakiniku stand, chicken cutlet
焼き肉屋台、チキンカツ
or charcoal grilled milk
または炭火焼きミルク
This rise is most pronounced
この上昇は最も顕著です
OK
OK
There are three leading military systems here
ここには 3 つの主要な軍事システムがあります
I'm actually about five meters away from them.
実際、私は彼らから約5メートル離れています。
In fact, it will also affect
実はそれも影響するんです
we know how serious
私たちはどれほど深刻かを知っています
And these like passing through the incense burner or the convenience store
香炉やコンビニの前を通るようなもの
Wait in the underground parking lot
地下駐車場でお待ちください
There are also such
そういったものもある
There is this obvious pick out
この明らかな選択があります
So in the future we will have a smaller one like this
したがって、将来的にはこのような小さなものを開発する予定です
some sensor words
いくつかのセンサーワード
can help us do more
私たちがもっとできるように助けてくれる
this
これ
Then this actually helps
それから、これは実際に役に立ちます
Ordinary people to understand his daily life
彼の日常生活を理解できる一般人
What kind of situation will it break into?
どのような状況に突入するのでしょうか？
it can change its behavior instantly
即座に行動を変えることができる
then reduce its risk
その後、そのリスクを軽減します
So this is our cooperation with the Information Office
これが情報局との協力です
Now there is a small
今は小さなものがあります
A portable version of the tiny sensor
小型センサーのポータブル版
This tiny sensor could also be added to the street
この小さなセンサーは街路にも追加できる可能性があります
with solar panels
ソーラーパネル付き
can then be transferred instantly to our database
その後、すぐにデータベースに転送できます
Even we have an indoor sensor like this
うちにもこのような屋内センサーがあります
OK
OK
The sensors in this room are also
この部屋のセンサーも
The data can be viewed online in real time
データはオンラインでリアルタイムに確認できます
At present, we have placed more than a dozen families
現在、十数家族を配置しています。
This is in a certain house
ここはとあるお家の中です
After months of data collection
数か月にわたるデータ収集の後
Also found A strange
奇妙なものも見つけました
Why does he have a fixed number of peaks every day
なぜ彼は毎日決まった回数のピークを持っているのでしょうか？
Spike concentrations of two or three
2 または 3 のスパイク濃度
Later I found out that he has the habit of offering incense in the morning and evening
後で知ったのですが、彼は朝と夕方にお線香をあげる習慣があるそうです。
And he cooks at home too
そして彼は家でも料理します
So we reminded him right away
そこで私たちはすぐに彼に思い出させました
He's very glad we reminded him
私たちが思い出させてくれたことを彼はとても喜んでくれました
This aunt also asked us later
このおばさんも後から聞いてきました
How can I reduce his concentration during this goodbye?
この別れの間、どうすれば彼の集中力を弱めることができるでしょうか?
We just reminded him to open the doors and windows
私たちは彼にドアと窓を開けるように念を押しただけです
So his concentration dropped a lot later
それで彼の集中力は後で大幅に低下しました
So this is what I think these tiny sensors
これが私が考えるこれらの小さなセンサーです
possible future development
今後の展開の可能性
is to remind everyone to change their behavior
全員に行動を変えるよう思い出させることです
reduce your health risks
健康リスクを軽減する
If we still hope in the future
まだ未来に希望があるなら
It is for this urban traffic flow
この都市交通の流れに
This is a collaboration with Mr. Fengyuan and the others
鳳源さん達とのコラボです
They have very good image recognition technology
彼らは非常に優れた画像認識技術を持っています
traffic in the community
コミュニティ内の交通
I think it must be an important factor causing the increase in pollution in this community
それがこの地域の汚染増加を引き起こす重要な要因に違いないと思います
Because there is no such good technology
そんなに優れた技術はないので
used to use very expensive cameras
以前は非常に高価なカメラを使用していました
to analyze
分析します
Now their technology can be used in general
現在、彼らの技術は一般的に使用できるようになりました
Everyone sees the police station hanging on the street
路上に警察署がぶら下がっているのを誰もが見る
or a government camera
または政府のカメラ
You can analyze the direction of the car
車の方向を分析できます
And it can identify the car type
そして車種も識別できる
Of course, this actually has many challenges.
もちろん、これには実際には多くの課題があります。
including say it you see there are so many different intersections
それを含めて、非常に多くの異なる交差点があることがわかります
it has a different turn
それは違う順番です
How to use a computer to directly identify
コンピュータを使用して直接識別する方法
Big cars and small cars can also be identified very well
大きな車と小さな車もよく識別できます
it has some shadowing due to the low angle
ローアングルのため多少のオクルージョンがあります
So it's a bad situation
だから悪い状況なんだよ
But otherwise
それ以外の場合
I think generally speaking, it is to analyze the traffic flow.
一般的に言えば、交通の流れを分析することだと思います。
is well analyzed
よく分析されています
In the future, we will cooperate with our observers on the street
今後は街頭監視員と協力していきます
So we are not afraid that this service company is lying to us
したがって、このサービス会社が私たちに嘘をついているのではないかと心配していません
We'll then be able to actually
そうすれば実際にできるようになります
Know the increase in emissions of vehicles that are not driving and the factors of emissions
走行していない車両の排出ガス増加と排出要因を知る
OK
OK
So if we do these emission factors and so on
したがって、これらの排出係数などを計算すると、
I hope it can be accumulated in our exposure mode in the future
将来的には露出モードで蓄積できるといいですね
OK
OK
Well, here's the stuff we've done over the years
さて、これが私たちが何年にもわたって行ってきたことです
Atmospheric
大気
this
これ
On weekends, I'd better go to the suburbs for a walk
週末は郊外へ散歩に行きたいです
Because it is true that the concentration in the suburbs is relatively low
郊外の集中度が相対的に低いのは事実なので
That secondhand smoke is the scariest
副流煙が一番怖い
OK so try not to smoke this one
わかったので、これは吸わないようにしてください
And after smoking your
そして、喫煙した後は、
The cilia in this lung will stop
この肺の繊毛は止まるだろう
30 minutes of inactivity
30 分間の非アクティブ状態
In other words, all your
言い換えれば、あなたのすべてが
All the dirt on the outside tends to get implanted deep in your lungs
外側の汚れはすべて肺の奥深くに植え込まれる傾向があります
OK
OK
so this can
これでできる
Tell your smoking friends
喫煙している友達に伝えてください
ask them to smoke as little as possible
できるだけ喫煙しないようにお願いします
Okay, the last mention is to say
さて、最後に言いたいのは、
In fact, it's not just the researchers who are very concerned about this PLO question.
実際、この PLO の問題について非常に懸念しているのは研究者だけではありません。
In fact, some civic groups
実際、一部の市民団体は、
They also spontaneously put this
彼らはこれも自発的に入れました
I cooperate with information agency
情報機関と連携しています
The prototype of a sensor developed by Mr. Lin Zhi and the others
林志氏らが開発したセンサーの試作機
after they improved
彼らが改善した後
There are also some private companies willing to mass produce
大量生産に意欲的な民間企業もいくつかある
Cooperate with some municipal governments, etc.
一部自治体等と連携
This is one of the airborne sensor network
これは航空機搭載センサー ネットワークの 1 つです
A Cooperative Mechanism of Industry, Government and Academia
産官学連携の仕組み
I also invited experts from European and American countries two weeks ago
２週間前にも欧米諸国から専門家を招聘した
they were also surprised
彼らも驚いていました
It is our air carrier sensor network in Taiwan
台湾の航空会社センサーネットワークです
This has accumulated to more than 2,000 sensors in the province
これは、州内の 2,000 個以上のセンサーに蓄積されました
Although he still has some accuracy problems
まだ精度の問題はあるものの、
But this can be improved by scientific correction
しかし、これは科学的な修正によって改善することができます
Finally, I would like to thank the hospital for this sustainable
最後に、この持続可能な医療を提供してくれた病院に感謝したいと思います。
Most of what I just reported was
私が今報告した内容のほとんどは
A collaborative effort of this sustainable project
この持続可能なプロジェクトの共同作業
This is a cross-disciplinary team
これは分野を超えたチームです
Thanks to my partners
パートナーのおかげで
We also want to say something about the results of our sustainable projects
持続可能なプロジェクトの結果についてもお話したいと思います
There can be some parts that can be used as a reference for government units
政府機関の参考になる部分もあるかもしれない
and can be translated into policy
ポリシーに変換できます
able to actually help everyone
実際にみんなを助けることができる
Can reduce health risks
健康リスクを軽減できる
protect our health
私たちの健康を守る
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, Mr. Long, very brilliant
ありがとう、ロングさん、とても素晴らしい
This introduction to 2D Hygan PM2.5
2D Hygan PM2.5 の紹介
now we have time left
今は時間が残っている
we're going to be open to questions
質問を受け付けます
If you ask questions today
今日質問するなら
We have a copy of the current issue of Scientific Man here
Scientific Man の最新号はここにあります
because there is an article in it
という記事があるので
Then give it to the friend who asked the question
それを質問した友人に渡します
we have seven on site
敷地内に7つあります
So the first seven people can get this magazine
ということで先着7名様にこの雑誌をプレゼント
If there are other problems later
後でまた問題が発生した場合
we don't have it right now
私たちには何もありません
just wait
ちょっと待って
Please register with the staff when you go out
お出かけの際はスタッフにお申し出ください
We just have questions today
今日は質問だけです
We'll deliver the magazine to you again
また雑誌をお届けします
ok , thanks then , one of you to start
わかりました、ありがとうございます、それでは始めてください
Excuse me
すみません
where is it
それはどこにある
because I looked
私が見たから
That thermal power plant in Taiwan
台湾のあの火力発電所
That PM2.5
あのPM2.5
Can you tell us about his numerical value?
彼の数値について教えていただけますか？
Do you mean the data he released?
彼が公開したデータのことですか？
This will probably go to the EPA
これはおそらくEPAに行くでしょう
What he said about the chimneys of thermal power plants
火力発電所の煙突について彼が語った事
They all have a direct
それらはすべて直接的なものを持っています
one...
一個...
You say it is an observation instrument
観測機器だと言うのですが
What he is observing is actually a light transmittance
彼が観察しているのは実際には光の透過率です
OK, this is connected to the environmental protection bureaus in various places
はい、これは各地の環境保護局につながっています
And now they are also connected to the Environmental Protection Agency
そして今、彼らは環境保護庁ともつながっています
have this business information
このビジネス情報を持っています
yes
はい
I don't have one for thermal power plants
火力発電所用は持っていない
thermal power plant for me
私にとっての火力発電所
It is an environment that affects the surrounding environment
周囲の環境に影響を与える環境です
an important factor
重要な要素
OK
OK
Then it has been mixed with the corona
そしたらコロナと混ざってしまった
so for me
だから私にとって
It is a monitoring station belonging to the Environmental Protection Agency
環境保護庁に属する監視局です
will study
勉強します
That is to say, the concentration that will be analyzed
つまり、分析される濃度は
Then I am researching mainly
それから主に研究しています
Above this ambient concentration
この周囲濃度を超えると
We'll also have some community polluters
地域社会にも汚染者がいるだろう
incremental increment
増分増分
even our personal behavior
私たちの個人的な行動さえも
will add this part of it again
この部分を再度追加します
This is the focus of my research
これが私の研究の焦点です
Thanks
ありがとう
ok this one
わかりました、これです
Hello Mr. Rong
こんにちは、ロンさん
excuse me, may I ask
すみません、聞いてもいいですか
Just two main questions
主な質問は 2 つだけです
inside a graph of your show
番組のグラフ内で
there is a 30
30はあります
We say that it will be dangerous after 32 o'clock
32時を過ぎると危険だそうです
But your paper got 36.8
でもあなたの論文は 36.8 点だった
I don't know why he took that paper
なぜ彼がその紙を受け取ったのか分かりません
The number of days is less or what is the meaning of this
日数が少ないとか、これはどういう意味ですか？
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
Second question you have a line plot of the WGBT distribution
2 番目の質問は、WGBT 分布の折れ線グラフです。
It looks like it works well together
相性が良さそうです
that approach a straight line at a time
一度に直線に近づく
It stands to reason that such data should be more suitable for prediction.
このようなデータが予測により適しているのは当然です。
Didn't our colleagues from the Meteorological Bureau say
気象庁の同僚が言ってなかったっけ？
The introduction said that if this is the case, our forecast is very accurate.
序論では、これが事実であれば、私たちの予測は非常に正確であると述べています。
Then can we push back and say
じゃあ、押し返して言ってもいいですか？
Such a linear function comes out to predict the value of
このような一次関数は、 の値を予測するために出てきます。
is it true what we say
私たちが言っていることは本当ですか
it is more predictive
それはより予測的です
Probably these two questions
おそらくこの2つの質問
Ok so the first one is 36.8 for this WGBT
さて、この WGBT の最初の値は 36.8 です
in fact it is
実際それは
Because if we want to issue hazard warnings,
なぜなら、危険警告を発したい場合は、
If you post every day for the whole summer
夏の間毎日投稿すると
That's the same thing as not publishing
出版しないのと同じことだ
There is no way to achieve the effect of early warning
早期警戒の効果を達成する方法はない
Because in fact, the meteorological unit is forecasting this situation every time.
なぜなら、実際、気象台は毎回この状況を予測しているからです。
I will remind everyone every day
毎日みんなに思い出させてあげるよ
It's just that there may be a heat hazard, etc.
熱害等の可能性があります。
That grows police words every day
警察の言葉が日に日に増えていく
it doesn't work
それは機能しません
So to find the nine percent
したがって、9パーセントを見つけるには
36.84% 99% quantile
36.84% 99% 分位数
That is to say, it is the one percent at the front end.
つまり、フロントエンドの 1 パーセントです。
right
右
So if we target
したがって、ターゲットを絞った場合
the top one percent
上位1パーセント
special reminder
特別なリマインダー
For example, let everyone
たとえば、みんなにしましょう
They all reduce going out
みんな外出を減らしてるよ
It is even said that there may be some more
他にもあるかもしれないとも言われています
including things like yelling with electricity
電気で叫ぶなども含む
Maybe don't use electricity at that time
その時は電気を使わないかも知れません
Because it is likely that everyone wants to turn on the air conditioner
たぶんみんなエアコンをつけたいと思うので
or how
あるいはどうやって
words like this
このような言葉
may be more effective
より効果的かもしれない
so this is
それでこれは
I think it is the consideration of the administrative unit
行政単位の配慮だと思います
they won't either
彼らもそうしないだろう
So this value is not fixed
したがって、この値は固定されていません
if later
後でしたら
About the market effect is higher
市場効果が高いことについて
or what he still raises like this
または彼が今でもこのように提起しているもの
yes
はい
Actually that's why
実はそれが理由です
set the warning of this heat hazard
この熱の危険性の警告を設定します
The limit is only
限界はただ
is so difficult
とても難しいです
because it's actually changing all the time
実際には常に変化しているので
A study in the United States also pointed out that
アメリカの研究でも次のようなことが指摘されています。
30 years ago and 30 years later
30年前も30年後も
the current one
現在的那個
They do heat hazards for this
彼らはこのために熱の危険をもたらします
The body does have, it should be said, an adjustment function
身体には調整機能があると言うべきです
That is, our body will slowly adjust to
つまり、私たちの体は徐々に順応していきます。
We can cope with hotter conditions
より暑い状況にも対応できます
Now I'm more worried
今はもっと心配です
In the context of the whole of our response to climate change shocks
気候変動の衝撃に対する私たちの対応全体の文脈において
Some people can adjust to the past, some people can't
過去に適応できる人もいるし、適応できない人もいる
So we still need the government to find a way
したがって、私たちは依然として政府が方法を見つける必要があります
Remind everyone with an early warning
早期警告で全員に知らせる
How come under some relatively hot conditions
比較的暑い状況下ではなぜそうなるのか
Able to do a good job in self-health management and self-protection
自己の健康管理と自己防衛をしっかりと行うことができる
So this is a purpose of heat warning
これは暑さ警報の目的です
This is the first point
これが最初のポイントです
the second you say that
それを言った瞬間に
we predicted this
私たちはこれを予測しました
this this line
この行
It is because meteorological units use complex physical and chemical
それは、気象単位が複雑な物理的および化学的要素を使用しているためです。
This model is used to make predictions
このモデルは予測を行うために使用されます
OK so all we can do now is
OK、それで今私たちにできることはこれだけです
The complex physicochemical patterns they predicted
彼らが予測した複雑な物理化学的パターン
made predictions
予測を立てた
We directly selected the temperature, humidity, wind speed and solar radiation
温度、湿度、風速、日射量を直接選択しました
convert it into WBGT
WBGTに変換します
Then compare it with our actual measured value
その後、当社の実測値と比較してください。
OK, our line came out like this
OK、私たちの行は次のようになりました
So you mean to use that line to make predictions directly
つまり、その行を使用して直接予測を行うということですね
Probably not what weather units are used to
おそらく気象観測装置が慣れているものではないでしょう
their words still apply
彼らの言葉は今でも当てはまります
Because they also have to take into account the flow of air masses and so on.
気団の流れなども考慮する必要があるからです。
i mean
つまり
can i just ask
ちょっと聞いてもいいですか
Maybe discuss it with the teacher of the Data Institute next time
今度データ研究所の先生に相談してみようかな
Because for us if the linear content
なぜなら、私たちにとってリニアなコンテンツであれば、
then you might be a math room
それならあなたは数学室かもしれない
then you can assess what the possible weaknesses are
次に、考えられる弱点が何であるかを評価できます
Or we should say that the surrounding area of ​​your linear derivative has the highest occurrence rate
あるいは、線形導関数の周囲の領域の出現率が最も高いと言うべきです。
yes but that's not our purpose
はい、でもそれは私たちの目的ではありません
We do that for the purpose of
私たちは次の目的でそれを行います
Check whether our measured values ​​are accurate to the predicted values
弊社の測定値が予測値に対して正確であるかどうかを確認します
That is to say, are they predicting well?
つまり、彼らはうまく予測しているのでしょうか？
Because the weather bureau is very concerned about what they're predicting
気象局は予測内容に非常に懸念しているからです
their models predict bad things
彼らのモデルは悪いことを予測します
So they are afraid to issue this warning
だから彼らはこの警告を発することを恐れている
no meaning
No 意思
So their purpose is to say
そこで彼らの目的はこう言うことです
Check that their models are currently predictive
モデルが現在予測可能であることを確認する
That's what we actually measure
それが私たちが実際に測定しているものです
These two places are also very close
この2つの場所もとても近いです
In this way, they are more at ease
このようにして、彼らはより安心します
Can do early warning of thermal hazards
熱による危険を早期に警告できる
So our purpose is actually like this
つまり、私たちの目的は実際には次のようなものです
do you mean
ということですか？
The prediction method of using the math room to push is inaccurate
数学室を使って押す予測方法は不正確です
No, it means meteorological units
いいえ、それは気象単位を意味します
they want to test
彼らはテストしたいのです
Meteorological unit to predict tomorrow's weather
明日の天気を予測する気象ユニット
It is actually a very complex pattern in the run
実際に実行すると非常に複雑なパターンになります
It is not a simple math room to push directly
直接プッシュできる単純な数学室ではありません
yes
はい
It's just that the food is more difficult
ただ、食事のほうが大変です。
ok we study too
はい、私たちも勉強します
We can discuss more later
後で詳しく話し合うことができます
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
there is one over there
あそこに1つあります
yes
はい
you say zhang hao
あなたは張昊と言います
i just mentioned
先ほど言いました
cataract problem
白内障の問題
you say you mean
あなたはそう言うのです
Under climate change maybe because of UV light and so on
紫外線などの影響による気候変動下
Effects on Cataracts
白内障への影響
this aspect
この側面
So far I haven't researched that
今のところそれについては調べていない
so deep
とても深い
The data analysis we are doing now
私たちが現在行っているデータ分析
The comparison is focused on the
比較の焦点は次のとおりです。
Neovascular disease Lung disease
血管新生疾患 肺疾患
Kidney disease, etc.
腎臓病など
some effects of this
これによるいくつかの効果
Then there are some studies pointing to skin disease
次に、皮膚疾患を指摘する研究がいくつかあります
that for this
それはこのために
This part of white goods is dirty
白物家電のこの部分は汚れています
We haven't done any research on this yet
これについてはまだ調査を行っていません
Thanks
ありがとう
In the future we can move towards this
将来的にはこれに向けて進むことができます
ok sir wait a minute
わかりました、ちょっと待ってください
May I ask if the current technology can lower the temperature?
現在の技術で温度を下げることができるかどうか聞いてもいいですか？
What can make the temperature of the earth
地球の温度は何によって決まるのか
or technology that cools the room down
または部屋を冷やす技術
Room temperature
室温
Indoor temperature is cold air
室内温度は冷気です
But I said the temperature of the entire earth
でも私は地球全体の温度を言いました
I am not in favor of using this geoengineering method to cool down
私はこの地球工学的手法を冷却目的に使用することに賛成ではありません。
Because I think there must be another sequelae
きっとまた後遺症があると思うから
This sequela is likely to be borne by people all over the world
この後遺症は世界中の人々が負う可能性がある
So I don't quite agree with scientists going to risk this blood
したがって、科学者たちがこの血液を危険にさらすことに同意することはできません
Come do the job of cooling the planet
地球を冷却する仕事に来てください
Or use this volley to clear it
またはこのボレーを使ってクリアしてください
It should be renewable energy
再生可能エネルギーであるべきだ
before reducing carbon emissions
二酸化炭素排出量を削減する前に
can slowly reduce the pace of climate change
気候変動のペースをゆっくりと減らすことができる
I think it's more of a way to draw the ground.
むしろ地面を描く方法だと思います。
Thanks
ありがとう
you talk about heat hazards
あなたは熱中症の危険性について話しています
Mainly it's like turning on the air conditioner
主にエアコンをつけるようなものです
Can I have indoor plants?
室内に植物を植えてもいいですか？
helps reduce temperature
体温を下げるのに役立ちます
Another reason I ask this is
私がこれを尋ねるもう一つの理由は、
I didn't see Mr. Lin Zhiming from the original branch in time
元の支店の林志明さんには間に合わなかった
he is tidying the garden
彼は庭を片付けています
Clean up the garden in the middle of the former branch office
旧出張所真ん中の庭掃除
He said it was hard to find
彼は見つけるのが難しいと言いました
So I would say plants have something to do with this
植物がこれに関係していると思います
well this is a
まあこれは
It's that plant that does provide shade
日陰を作ってくれるのはあの植物です
So it's not just
だからそれだけではない
In fact, the urban green space
実は都市の緑地は、
will have a cooling effect on local areas
局地的な地域に影響を与えるだろう
In the house, planting plants in the corridor and so on will indeed have a cooling effect
家の中でも廊下などに植物を植えると確かに冷房効果があります。
Some scientific literature has some such reports
一部の科学文献にはそのような報告があります
In fact, the researchers of our doctoral association have also done some urban green space planning on the impact of cooling
実際、私たちの博士協会の研究者たちは、冷房の影響について都市緑地計画も行っています。
So we also have measured rulings in this area, etc.
したがって、この分野の裁定なども測定しました。
And it can provide some job opportunities, which is a problem
そして、それはいくつかの雇用の機会を提供する可能性がありますが、それは問題です
Then, at the beginning, you said that 90% of the TV room and theater room are green.
それで、最初にテレビ室とシアタールームの9割が緑だとおっしゃいました。
And internet surveys are cheap but young people
そして、インターネット調査は安価ですが、若者は
Is there a way to combine
組み合わせる方法はありますか
That means doing some research online and asking him to ask his family.
それは、ネットで調べたり、家族に聞いてもらうことを意味します。
Then use those cost gaps as lectures or commentary to encourage them
そして、それらのコストギャップを講義や解説として利用して、彼らを奨励します。
Thank you. We've actually thought about this before.
ありがとう。実はこれについては以前にも考えたことがあります。
But the more troublesome thing is that you have to train the middleman
しかし、もっと厄介なことは、仲介者を訓練しなければならないことです
In fact, all of us interviewers have to come to us for three days of training.
実際、私たち面接官は全員、3 日間の研修を受けなければなりません。
Actually quite hard
実はかなり大変
So if we use questionnaires to survey young people on the Internet
したがって、アンケートを使用してインターネット上で若者を調査すると、
We're still trying to figure out how to train this young man
私たちはこの若者をどのように訓練するかをまだ模索中です
and then ask his grandparents
そして祖父母に聞いてみる
we thought about it
私たちはそれについて考えました
But in practice, it is quite difficult
しかし、実際にやってみるとなかなか難しいのです
Thanks
ありがとう
Another question is
もう一つの質問は、
We talk about the situation at home and abroad, just the opposite
国内外の逆の状況について話します
It’s just that in foreign countries, their interiors are rather dirty
ただ、外国では内装が汚いです
The opposite is true in Taiwan
台湾では状況が全く逆です
You are talking about the comparison between indoor and outdoor
屋内と屋外の比較について話しています
Is it possible for the two countries to be at the same time?
両国が同時に存在することは可能でしょうか？
definitely worth comparing
間違いなく比較する価値があります
Of course we are worse than America
もちろんアメリカよりも劣っている
much worse
ずっと悪いです
how bad is it
どれくらい悪い
We can use the data on the Internet to see
インターネット上のデータを使用して見ることができます
Because many places in the United States
アメリカの多くの場所にあるので、
It is possible to meet this annual average
この年間平均を達成することは可能です
15 micrograms per cubic meter
1立方メートルあたり15マイクログラム
Some can even be better than 10
10 を超えるものもあります
Then Taiwan basically only has Huadong
となると台湾には基本的に華東しかない
Only barely around 15
ギリギリ15くらいかな
That is to say, although they are dirty indoors
つまり、室内は汚いのですが、
But still cleaner than our outdoor
それでも屋外よりはきれいです
this one
これです
good
良い
Our one will be right back
私たちのものはすぐに戻ってきます
can i hear you answer this question
この質問に答えるのを聞いてもいいですか
Whether we are in Europe or Asia
ヨーロッパにいてもアジアにいても
Pollution both outdoors and indoors
屋外と屋内の両方での汚染
but in asia
でもアジアでは
the outdoor pollution
屋外の汚染
Once inside, it settles
中に入ると落ち着く
so every day we have to wipe the table
だから毎日テーブルを拭かなければならない
is a sedimented
沈殿したものです
but in europe
しかしヨーロッパでは
Because outdoor pollution is less
屋外の汚染が少ないため
So indoor cooking is relatively high
なので室内調理は比較的高いです
this is relatively
これは比較的です
We're down because we're indoors
屋内にいるので落ち込んでいます
so viewers come
だから視聴者が来る
the air will be clean
空気がきれいになります
Thank you Dean Li
ありがとうディーン・リー
Thank you for the supplementary answer
補足回答ありがとうございます
Just this gentleman
ただこの紳士
I just noticed that a data is the data ratio
データとはデータ比率であることに今気づきました
much smaller than that of a smoker
喫煙者よりもはるかに小さい
This is not what I expected
これは私が期待していたものではありません
That is to say, it should be one
つまり、1つである必要があります
It should be that the so-called BN2.5 data will sing very high
いわゆるBN2.5データは非常に高い値を示すはずです
The result of that tiny detector
その小さな検出器の結果
That's because you really smoke
それはあなたが本当にタバコを吸うからです
After a smoker's stats are so high
喫煙者の統計が非常に高いため、
Or is it a detector issue?
それとも探知機の問題でしょうか？
we passed by
私たちは通り過ぎました
Are you talking about the information about the night market?
夜市の情報のことですか？
yes
はい
The night market information is actually three smokers
夜市情報は実は喫煙者3名
And they've been smoking there for a while
そして彼らはしばらくそこでタバコを吸っていました
So this time answer first
そこで今回は先に答えてください
that kissing words
そのキスの言葉
we just pass by
私たちは通り過ぎるだけです
We're not actually that close to it
実際にはそこまで近づいていない
didn't mean to
そんなつもりはなかった
But speaking of distance
でも距離で言えば
We may be close to that distance
私たちはその距離に近づいているかもしれない
Probably about the same as the smoker
たぶん喫煙者と同じくらい
So in fact, it is to look at the inside of the temple.
ということで、実際はお寺の内部を見学することになります。
A little more is actually related to how many boxes
もう少し多くは、実際にはボックスの数に関係します
So that's the result of our test
これが私たちのテストの結果です
ok, this one has
わかりました、これにはあります
let me ask
聞いてもいいですか
on your side
あなたの側に
That's this number for PM2.5
これがPM2.5の数値です
It is obvious that the graph line has dropped in recent years
近年グラフの線が下がっているのは明らか
But in our impression
しかし、私たちの印象では、
Because our PM2.5
なぜなら私たちのPM2.5は
So the Air and Oxygen Bureau exploded in the past few years
つまり、大気酸素局はここ数年で爆発したのです
just started to have these forecasts
こういった予測が始まったばかりです
that and we see what a place it is these years
それがここ数年でどれほどの場所であるかがわかりました
It seems that they are all red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red red
どうやらみんなあかあかあかあかあかあかあかあかあかあかあかあかあかああああああああああああああああああああ
a lot of them
それらの多く
So in our sense
つまり、私たちの感覚では
It seems that PM2.5 is very serious now
今PM2.5がかなり深刻なようです
There is also a second question
2 番目の質問があります
I used to ask that Puri
プリによく聞いてた
when purina side
ピュリナ側の場合
We used to say that Puri is like good water
私たちはプリはおいしい水のようなものだとよく言いました
is a good view
良い眺めです
best air
最高の空気
But when Purina turned out to be
しかし、ピュリナがそうなったとき、
When the whole province of Taiwan
台湾全土になると、
2.5% seems to be the highest today
今日は2.5%が最高のようです
why is that
何故ですか
ok , to answer your first question
OK、最初の質問に答えます
The first question is actually usually
最初の質問は実際には通常、
Pollution is more serious in winter
汚染は冬にさらに深刻になる
especially in south central
特に中南部では
Pollution is serious in winter
冬は公害が深刻
But if we average it out
しかし、それを平均してみると
It is actually an annual average
実際は年間平均です
In summer, it is actually less polluted
夏は実際に汚染が少ない
OK
OK
So if you look at the annual average in winter and summer
冬と夏の年間平均を見ると、
will be averaged out
平均化されます
Then you said that it is red every day
そしたら毎日赤いって言ってたね
That's actually mostly in winter.
それは実際には冬がほとんどです。
especially in this
特にこれでは
There is indeed a lot of pollution in Kaohsiung.
確かに高雄は汚染がひどい。
Actually quite serious
実はかなり深刻
right
右
Then there is another question, that is
それから、別の質問があります。
Back then when the environmental groups released this air pollution period
環境保護団体が大気汚染期間を発表した当時
It's often an hour's worth of data
多くの場合、1 時間相当のデータになります
To compare the environmental protection number is actually an average of 24 hours
環境保護数値を比較すると、実際には平均 24 時間です
that is
あれは
This is the standard of air pollution
これが大気汚染の基準です
OK, it's actually not suitable
そうですね、実際にはふさわしくありません
Theoretically, it is necessary to accumulate 24 hours
理論的には24時間蓄積する必要がある
Ability to go beyond the 24 hour standard
24時間基準を超える能力
There is no one-hour standard for the environmental protection number
環境保護数値には1時間の基準はない
then we actually think
それから私たちは実際に考えます
Might want to consider having an hour standard
時間基準を設けることを検討するとよいでしょう
Because like I just mentioned
なぜなら、先ほど述べたように
In fact, P2.5 is for acute
実際、P2.5は急性のものです
It actually has acute health effects
実は健康に重大な影響を与える
Then why is there no acute
ではなぜ急性期がないのか
It is the standard of one hour of agricultural degree
農業1時間の目安です
because there is no good scientific data to back it up
それを裏付ける適切な科学的データがないからです
Tell us what kind of farming it is
どのような農業なのか教えてください
There will be such acute health damage
このような深刻な健康被害が発生するでしょう
So if there is good scientific evidence
それで、きちんとした科学的証拠があれば
Then the future can slowly move towards
そうすれば未来はゆっくりと向かっていくことができる
How to build such an hour of air though
しかし、そのような空気をどのように構築するか
Restricted standards to move forward
前進するための制限された基準
The second question is Puri
2番目の質問はプリです
Puri's problem is
プリちゃんの問題は、
Puri actually
実はプリ
let me say it again
もう一度言わせてください
when puri was the one
プリのとき
We used to say Puri was the cleanest
私たちはプリが最もクリーンだと言っていた
But in the past few years
しかしここ数年で
when puri's side of them
プリが彼らの側にいるとき
The information found is the most serious P2.5 in Taiwan
発見された情報はおそらく台湾で最も深刻なP2.5
why is that so
どうしてこんなことに
It's Puri this we actually
実はこれがプリなんです
The whole team around the center
チーム全員がセンターを囲む
Including myself, I have been the deputy director of customs clearance in the lead
私を含めて、私は税関の次長を率いてきました。
And then we're actually here
そして、私たちは実際にここにいます
Since last year there has been pollution targeting this area in central Puri
昨年以来、プリ中心部のこの地域をターゲットとした汚染が発生しています
have started doing some research
いくつかの研究を始めました
This part of Napuri may be derived from the part of Taichung
ナプリのこの部分は台中の部分から派生した可能性があります
from Taichung
台中から
There are also some possibly local motorbikes
おそらく地元のバイクもいくつかあります
Because the accumulation is there and can't get out
溜まって抜け出せないから
Because after all, it is a situation in a relatively mountainous area.
やはり比較的山間部の状況でございますので。
Both are possible
どちらも可能です
For now, we'll need more scientific evidence
今のところ、より多くの科学的証拠が必要です
to know why
理由を知るために
It will cause such a serious pollution in Puri
それはプリにこのような深刻な汚染を引き起こすでしょう
Thanks
ありがとう
good
良い
There is a kid here
ここに子供がいます
Hello teacher
こんにちは先生
i want to ask
聞きたいです
Which method does the teacher recommend to prevent weak hazards?
弱いハザードを防ぐために先生が推奨する方法はどれですか?
What kind
何の種類
do you defend yourself
あなたは自分自身を守りますか
just at home
ただ家にいるだけ
I usually wash my face at home
私は普段家で顔を洗っていますが、
Heat dissipation and drinking the Aiyu just mentioned
放熱と先ほどの愛湯の飲用
I think it's more cooling
もっと涼しいと思うよ
and not to the body
そして体にではなく
Because Aiyu it's not so cool
アイユはかっこよくないから
so you know girls sometimes
だからあなたは時々女の子を知っていますか？
Don't drink anything too cold
あまりにも冷たいものを飲まないでください
But Aiyu should be fine
でもアイユなら大丈夫だよ
So for the body there will be no
したがって、体には何もありません
Too bad some of the other side effects
他のいくつかの副作用が残念です
second question
2番目の質問
ask about the room
部屋について尋ねる
Now there are a lot of air purifiers
今は空気清浄機もたくさんありますが、
Can it filter PH2.5 and PH1.0
PH2.5とPH1.0をフィルターできますか
What about indoor air quality
室内空気の質はどうですか
Is there an actual effect
実際に効果はあるのか
there are some indeed in this
この中には確かにいくつかあります
I know some researchers
私は何人かの研究者を知っています
some of the air cleaners they sell for homes
家庭用に販売されている空気清浄機の一部
But that was done seven or eight years ago
でもそれは7、8年前に行われたことだ
Basically only one effective
基本的に有効なのは1つだけ
Now the technology is better
今は技術も良くなってるし
So there should be more effective
だからもっと効果的なものがあるはずだ
Then I'm going to talk about the only one they made that worked seven or eight years ago
それから私は彼らが7、8年前に作った唯一の機能について話します
In fact, it's too expensive, and most people won't use it at all.
実際、それは高すぎるため、ほとんどの人はまったく使用しません。
so you know it's
だからあなたはそれが知っています
i mean
つまり
Generally affordable ones are likely to have no effect
一般的に手頃な価格のものは効果がない可能性が高い
i'm embarrassed to say that
それを言うのが恥ずかしいです
but
しかし
But now technology has improved
でも今は技術も進歩してるから
From another perspective
別の観点から見ると
This question to students we should say
学生たちにこの質問を言うべきです
Actually, I haven't tested it.
実際、テストしたことはありません。
I don't know. I didn't test it myself.
わかりません。自分でテストしたわけではありません。
Ok, then I also buy air purifiers at home
よし、それなら家にも空気清浄機を買おう
Then I should try it next time with mine
じゃあ今度は私のもので試してみようかな
simple setting
簡単な設定
Micro-sense test to see if it works
機能するかどうかを確認するためのマイクロセンステスト
Thank you teacher for your answer
先生、ご回答ありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
There are many kinds of air proximity devices
空中近接装置にはさまざまな種類があります
It's only used in hospitals now
現在は病院でのみ使用されています
this in the hospital
これは病院で
Air Proximator
エアプロキシメーター
about one step
一歩くらい
three hundred thousand dollars
30万ドル
that for pm2
それはpm2用です
Today I was helpful, others were not
今日私は役に立ちましたが、他の人は役に立ちませんでした
Thank you, Dean Li, for helping me answer this question.
この質問への回答にご協力いただき、ディーン・リーさんに感謝します。
This is the authority on chemistry
これが化学の権威です
Okay, we have about four minutes.
さて、あと 4 分ほどあります。
let me ask the last question myself
最後の質問を私自身にさせてください
Because you can see the distribution of your WBGT in your
WBGT の分布は、
You said that the highest and worst place in New Taipei City is Yonghe
新北市で一番高くて最悪の場所は永和だと言いましたね
Because it may be very crowded and crowded there.
そこは非常に混雑していて混雑している可能性があるためです。
Then there are many houses and the streets are relatively narrow
それから家がたくさんあり、道は比較的狭いです
The worst place in Taipei City is Zhongzheng District
台北市で最悪の場所は中正区です
It's a bit Zhongzheng District, my impression is
ちょっと中正区っぽい印象です。
This population is not that much
この人口はそれほど多くない
Then the streets are wider
そしたら道も広くなるよ
Yes you know why that place
はい、なぜその場所か知っていますか
It's still a lot of water, there's too much Pojoro, or something
まだ水が多すぎる、ポジョロが多すぎる、または何か
Why is it worse over there?
なぜあそこはもっとひどいのですか？
If we do this, of course we counted this at that time
これをやれば、もちろんその時はこれを数えました
Just mentioned that heat island
先ほどヒートアイランドのことを言いました
heat island effect
ヒートアイランド現象
The heat island effect is actually not in Zhongzheng District
ヒートアイランド現象は実は中正区ではない
not the worst part
最悪の部分ではない
So we are also curious
だから私たちも興味津々です
But you can see that the area
しかし、見てわかるように、この地域は
So it is also related to the temperature distribution at that time
その時の温度分布も関係しているんですね
is about
についてです
That's actually like Nangang's words
まさに南港さんの言葉ですね
Relatively speaking, the temperature in Nangang
相対的に南港の気温は
In fact, it is not as high as downtown Taipei.
実際、台北のダウンタウンほど高くはありません。
So this is also related to the temperature at that time
これはその時の気温も関係しているのですね
right
右
good
良い
Then our time is almost up
それでは時間も終わりに近づいています
we are very thankful today
今日はとても感謝しています
Teacher Long Shijun gave us such a wonderful speech
龍世軍先生がとても素晴らしいスピーチをしてくださいました
We give him another round of applause
私たちは彼にもう一度拍手を送ります
Thanks
ありがとう
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました